. >> GOOD AFTERNOON WELCOME TO
THE JULY 8TH 2025 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN FRANCISCO
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. >> MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL? THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY PRESENT SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO
AND ENGARDIO PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR FIELDER.
FIELDER PRESENT SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD PRESENTS
SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN PRESIDENT MANDOLIN PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR
MELGAR MELGAR PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR SADR SADR PRESENT
SUPERVISOR CHERYL SHERYL PRESENT AND SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON PRESENT. MR. PRESIDENT ALL MEMBERS ARE
PRESENT. >> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK.
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT
WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL HOMELAND OF THE ROMA ALONI WHO
THEY ARE THE ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PENINSULA. AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF
THIS LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE RAW
MATERIALS MANY HAVE NEVER CEDED LOST NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR
RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS
WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL
TERRITORY. AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE
BENEFIT FROM LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOME LAND.
WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS,
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE ROMA ALONI COMMUNITY AND BY
AFFIRMING THEIR SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST PEOPLES.
COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF
ALLEGIANCE? I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG
OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA AND TO THE REPUBLIC FOR WHICH
IT STANDS ONE NATION UNDER GOD, INDIVISIBLE, WITH LIBERTY
AND JUSTICE FOR ALL. >> ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I
WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF AT US OF GOTV AND TODAY
PARTICULARLY KALEENA MENDOZA WHO RECORD EACH OF OUR MEETINGS
AND MAKE THE TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE PUBLIC ONLINE.
MADAM CLERK, DO YOU HAVE ANY COMMUNICATIONS?
>> MR. PRESIDENT, THE SPECIAL ORDER AT 2 P.M..
OKAY. SO LET'S GO TO OUR 2 P.M.
SPECIAL ORDER. YES.
THE SPECIAL ORDER AT TWO IS THE APPEARANCE BY THE HONORABLE
MAYOR DANIEL LURIE. THERE BEING NO QUESTIONS
SUBMITTED FROM ELIGIBLE DISTRICTS.
THE MAYOR MAY ADDRESS THE BOARD FOR UP TO FIVE MINUTES.
>> ALL RIGHTS. >> WELCOME, MR. MAYOR.
WE HAVE NO TOPIC SUBMITTED FOR TODAY.
>> SO WE'RE GOING TO HEAR FROM YOU FOR UP TO FIVE MINUTES.
GOOD AFTERNOON. BOARD PRESIDENT MANAGEMENT
AND MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
TODAY MARKS SIX MONTHS SINCE I TOOK OFFICE.
WE STILL HAVE WORK AHEAD. BUT CITY HALL IS DEMONSTRATING
WHAT A NEW ERA OF COLLABORATION CAN ACHIEVE.
WE'RE ON TRACK TO CLOSE AN $800 MILLION BUDGET DEFICIT WHILE
INVESTING IN OUR RECOVERY STRENGTHENING PUBLIC SAFETY
STAFFING. TAKING BOLD ACTION TO ADDRESS
OUR HOMELESSNESS AND BEHAVIORAL HEALTH CRISIS.
AND ADVANCING LEGISLATION TO STREAMLINE PERMITTING AND BUILD
MORE HOUSING. NONE OF THIS PROGRESS WOULD BE
POSSIBLE WITHOUT THIS BOARD. OVER THE PAST SIX MONTHS I'VE
WORKED CLOSELY WITH EACH OF YOU ON LEGISLATION AND BUDGET
PRIORITIES THAT REFLECT OUR SHARED COMMITMENT TO THIS CITY
. THROUGHOUT THIS SPRING
SUPERVISOR CHAN AND I ENGAGED IN DEEP DISCUSSIONS AROUND THE
BUDGET AND PRIORITIES FOR SAN FRANCISCO.
THIS YEAR'S BUDGET OFFERED FEW GOOD OPTIONS BUT I'M GRATEFUL
TO CHAIR CHAN FOR HELPING GUIDE OUR CITY TOWARD FISCAL
SUSTAINABILITY. ALSO IN THIS SPRING SUPERVISOR
CHERYL AND I INTRODUCED LEGISLATION TO RENEW FIRST YEAR
FREE. MAKING IT EASIER FOR SMALL
BUSINESSES TO LAUNCH AND GROW IN SAN FRANCISCO.
LATER THIS WEEK WE WILL SIGN THAT LEGISLATION INTO LAW.
LAST MONTH SUPERVISOR SAUTNER AND I INTRODUCED LEGISLATION
FOR 530 SANSOM A PROJECT THAT WILL DELIVER A NEW FIRE
STATION, HOTEL AND OFFICE SPACE.
WHILE CONTRIBUTING MILLIONS OF DOLLARS FOR AFFORDABLE HOUSING
. EARLIER THIS YEAR SUPERVISOR
AND GUARDIAN AND I MET WITH NEIGHBORS ALONG SUNSET
BOULEVARD TO DISCUSS MUCH NEEDED IMPROVEMENTS TO THAT
MEDIAN. THIS BUDGET DELIVERS ON THOSE
IMPROVEMENTS. TWO WEEKS AGO SUPERVISOR MAHMUD
AND I HELD A SIGNING CEREMONY AT KEZAR STADIUM TO CELEBRATE A
$10 MILLION INVESTMENT FROM GOLDEN CITY FC AND THE ARRIVAL
OF SAN FRANCISCO'S NEWEST PROFESSIONAL SPORTS TEAM
IN MAY. SURROUNDED BY THE RECOVERY
COMMUNITY, WE SIGNED SUPERVISOR DORSEY'S LEGISLATION DECLARING
SAN FRANCISCO A RECOVERY FIRST CITY.
TOMORROW THE BUDGET AND FINANCE COMMITTEE WILL HEAR A PROPOSAL
DEVELOPED BY MY OFFICE IN PARTNERSHIP WITH SUPERVISOR
MELGAR TO ADDRESS THE ISSUES OF RV ENCAMPMENTS AN EFFORT TO
PROVIDE BETTER OPTIONS FOR THE PEOPLE LIVING IN THEM
AND IMPROVE CONDITIONS FOR OUR NEIGHBORHOODS.
IN DISTRICT NINE I WORKED WITH SUPERVISOR FIELDER TO ESTABLISH
THE CITY'S NEWEST ENTERTAINMENT ZONE ON VALENCIA STREET
IN DISTRICT TEN. SUPERVISOR WALTON AND I ARE
WORKING WITH COMMUNITY ON THE BEST APPROACH TO JEREL COMMON
SHELTER SITE TO ENSURE DISTRICT TEN IS AT THE TABLE FOR FUTURE
DECISIONS IN DISTRICT 11. >> WE'RE PARTNERING WITH
SUPERVISOR CHAN TO ENSURE CAPITAL INVESTMENTS IN THE
EXCELSIOR OMI AND CROCKER AMAZON DELIVER FOR FAMILIES
CHILDREN AND SENIORS. AND NONE OF THIS WOULD BE
POSSIBLE WITHOUT BOARD PRESIDENT RAFAEL MANMOHAN FROM
THE FENNEL ORDINANCE TO MY BREAKING THE CYCLE EXECUTIVE
DIRECTOR FROM SUPPORTING CANCER SCREENING FOR FIREFIGHTERS TO A
WORK TO ADDRESSING STREET CONDITIONS IN THE CASTRO.
THERE ARE FEW ISSUES POLICY OR DISTRICT SPECIFIC WHERE I HAVE
INSIGHT HIS ADVICE, SUPPORT OR COLLABORATION.
TOGETHER WE ARE SHOWING OUR RESIDENTS AND VISITORS THAT WE
ARE FOCUSED ON WHAT MATTERS. PUBLIC SAFETY, CLEAN STREETS
AND A STRONG ECONOMIC RECOVERY. AS WE FINALIZE THE BUDGET WE'RE
ALSO ADVANCING KEY PRIORITIES OUR FAMILY ZONING PLAN TO KEEP
SAN FRANCISCO AFFORDABLE FOR OUR NEXT GENERATION OUR
PERMANENT S.F. PLAN TO CUT RED TAPE FOR SMALL BUSINESSES
AND OUR RV PLAN TO BRING COMPASSION, SAFETY AND ORDER TO
OUR STREETS. I WANT TO THANK YOU ALL FOR
YOUR PARTNERSHIP. I LOOK FORWARD TO THE NEXT SIX
MONTHS AS WE CONTINUE TO DELIVER FOR THE PEOPLE OF SAN
FRANCISCO. >> THANK YOU, BOARD PRESIDENT.
THANK YOU. MAYOR LURIE, CONGRATULATIONS ON
YOUR FIRST SIX MONTHS. >> THANK YOU, SIR.
GOOD TO SEE YOU. THANK YOU ALL.
>> ALL RIGHT. THIS MATTER HAS BEEN DISCUSSED
AND IS NOW FILED. >> AND MADAM CLERK, I THINK YOU
MAY HAVE HAD SOME COMMUNICATIONS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT. YES, THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS WELCOMES ALL THE MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC HERE
IN THE CHAMBER TO ATTEND THIS MEETING IN PERSON.
WHERE IN THE BOARD'S CHAMBERS. SECOND FLOOR ROOM 250 WITHIN
CITY HALL. OR IF YOU CAN'T MAKE IT DOWN
HERE YOU CAN WATCH THE PROCEEDING ON S.F. GOV TV'S
CHANNEL 26 OR VIEW THE LIVE STREAM AT W UWW DOT SMG OR
VTV.ORG. >> FOR ITEMS THREE THROUGH 32.
THESE ARE THE ITEMS THAT COMPRISE THE CITY'S BUDGET.
THEY HAVE HAD THEIR PUBLIC COMMENT IN COMMITTEE AND YOU
ARE NOT ABLE TO SPEAK ON THE BUDGET TODAY.
DURING GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT BUT IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO
PROVIDE ANY WRITTEN COMMENT ON ANY OTHER ITEMS YOU CAN SEND AN
EMAIL TO BE OFFSET AS HAVE GOV DAWG OR USE THE U.S. POSTAL
SERVICE AND JUST ADDRESS THE ENVELOPE TO THE SAN FRANCISCO
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS AS THE NUMBER ONE DR. CARLETON
CAPITAL. BE PERIOD GOOD LITTLE PLACE
CITY HALL ROOM 244 IN SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA 94102.
>> AND THE LAST TWO COMMENTS ARE THAT IF YOU NEED TO MAKE A
REASONABLE ACCOMMODATION REQUEST UNDER THE AMERICANS
WITH DISABILITIES ACT OR IF YOU NEED TO REQUEST LANGUAGE
ASSISTANCE, PLEASE CONTACT THE CLERK'S OFFICE AT LEAST TWO
BUSINESS DAYS IN ADVANCE OR BY CALLING (415) 554-5184.
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
>> LET'S GO TO THE APPROVAL OF OUR MEETING MINUTES.
APPROVAL OF THE JUNE THIRD, 2025 BOARD MEETING MINUTES.
>> COLLEAGUES, I DON'T THINK ANYONE HAS ANY CHANGES SO CAN I
HAVE A MOTION TO APPROVE THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED A MOVE BY
CHAN SECONDED BY WALTON. >> MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED?
>> SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I'M A SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO
AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI MANDELL MAN I
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISORS SORTER SAUTER I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I AND SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
THERE ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MINUTES WILL BE
APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC COMMENT AS PRESENTED MADAM CLERK LET'S
GO TO THE CONSENT AGENDA ITEMS ONE AND TWO ITEMS ONE AND TWO
ARE ON CONSENT. THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED TO
BE ROUTINE IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY BE REMOVED
AND CONSIDERED SEPARATELY. >> MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON THE CONSENTED FORMS ONE AND TWO SUPERVISOR
CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY
DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI MENDELSON I'M SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR EYES SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL
CHERYL I AND SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EITHER ARE LEBANESE
WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY PASSED
MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO NEW BUSINESS AND INTRODUCTION OF
THE BUDGET PLEASE CALL ITEMS THREE THROUGH 32 TOGETHER ITEM
THREE THROUGH 32 PERTAINING TO THE CITY'S BUDGET AND PURSUANT
TO CHARTER SECTION 9.100 B THE BOARD SHALL NOT ADOPT THE
BUDGET ANY EARLIER THAN JULY 15TH NOR LATER THAN AUGUST 1ST
. ITEM THREE IS THE BUDGET
APPROPRIATION ORDINANCE THAT APPROPRIATES ALL ESTIMATED
RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR DEPARTMENTS OF THE CITY
AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO AS OF MAY 30TH 2025 FOR THE FISCAL
YEAR ENDING JUNE 30TH 2026 AND JUNE 30TH 2027.
ITEM FOUR IS THE ANNUAL SALARY ORDINANCE THAT ENUMERATES
POSITIONS IN THE ANNUAL BUDGET AND APPROPRIATION ORDINANCE FOR
THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30TH, 2026 AND JUNE 30TH 2027.
ITEM FIVE THIS ORDINANCE AMENDS THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO
MODIFY THE SHORT TERM LICENSE FEES FOR THE USE OF CITY HALL.
ITEM SIX AMENDS THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO
TRANSFERRING DATA COLLECTION OVERSIGHT DUTIES FROM THE CITY
ADMINISTRATOR TO THE HUMAN RIGHTS COMMISSION AS WELL AS
REMOVES OBSOLETE REPORTING REQUIREMENTS.
ITEM SEVEN THIS ORDINANCE AMENDS THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE
TO CLARIFY THE STATUS OF THE TREASURE ISLAND DEVELOPMENT
AUTHORITY AS A CITY DEPARTMENT .
ITEM EIGHT THIS ORDINANCE AMENDING THE ADMINISTRATIVE
CODE TO ELIMINATE THE BUDGET SAVINGS INCENTIVE FUND ITEM
NINE THIS ORDINANCE ADOPTS THE NEIGHBORHOOD BEAUTIFICATION
AND GRAFFITI CLEANUP FUND TAX DESIGNATION CEILING FOR TAX
YEAR 2025 ITEM TEN THIS ORDINANCE MODIFIES THE BASELINE
FUNDING REQUIREMENT FOR EARLY CARE AND EDUCATION PROGRAMS TO
ENABLE THE CITY TO USE THE INTEREST EARNED FROM THE EARLY
CARE AND EDUCATION COMMERCIAL RENTS TAX FOR THOSE BASELINE
PROGRAMS. ITEM TEN THIS ORDINANCE
RETROACTIVELY AUTHORIZES SES, THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC
DEFENDERS OFFICE TO ACCEPT AN EXPENDED $3.4 MILLION GRANT
FROM THE CRAIG START FOUNDATION TO EXPAND THE CAPACITY OF THE
IMMIGRATION DEFENSE UNIT TO MEET THE INCREASED DEMAND FOR
SERVICES. >> IT ALSO AMENDS THE ANNUAL
SALARY ORDINANCE TO PROVIDE FOR FOUR GRANT FUNDED POSITIONS
8177 ATTORNEYS AND A CLASS 8173 LEGAL ASSISTANT.
ITEM 12 THIS ORDINANCE AMENDING THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO
AUTHORIZE FEES FOR VEHICLES REGISTERED TO A SAN FRANCISCO
ADDRESS TO FUND LAW ENFORCEMENT PROGRAMS RELATED TO FINGERPRINT
IDENTIFICATION OF PERSONS INVOLVED IN CRIMES COMMITTED
WHILE OPERATING MOTOR VEHICLES IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE
CALIFORNIA STATE LAW AND TO ESTABLISH THE POLICE
FINGERPRINT IDENTIFICATION FUND TO RECEIVE THE FEE REVENUE ITEM
13 THIS ORDINANCE APPROPRIATES AND D APPROPRIATE IT'S A TOTAL
NET D APPROPRIATION AMOUNT OF APPROXIMATELY 87,000 FROM A
PREVIOUSLY APPROVED ORDINANCE NUMBER 124 DASH 24 FOR THE SAN
FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION CAPITAL PROJECTS
BUDGETS AND SUPPLEMENTAL APPROPRIATION ITEM 14 THIS
ORDINANCE AUTHORIZES THE ISSUANCE AND SALE OF TAX EXEMPT
OR TAXABLE WATER REVENUE BONDS AND OTHER FORMS OF INDEBTEDNESS
BY THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION FOR AN
APPROXIMATE AMOUNT OF 1 BILLION TO FINANCE COSTS OF VARIOUS
CAPITAL WATER AND HETCH HETCHY WATER PROJECTS BENEFITING THE
WATER ENTERPRISE ITEM 15 THIS ORDINANCE D APPROPRIATES
APPROXIMATELY 13 MILLION IN THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES
COMMISSION TO BENEFIT THE WATER ENTERPRISE DIVISION ITEM 16
THIS ORDINANCE AMENDS THE PART CODE TO AUTHORIZE THE
RECREATION AND PARKS DEPARTMENT TO CHARGE FEES FOR RESERVING
TENNIS AND PICKLEBALL COURTS AT LOCATIONS OTHER THAN THE GOLDEN
GATE PARK TENNIS CENTER AND AFFIRMS SEQUEL
DETERMINATIONS. ITEM 17 AMENDS THE PARK CODE TO
ALLOW THE RECREATION AND PARK DEPARTMENT TO SET FEES FOR
RECREATION PROGRAMS BASED ON THE DEPARTMENT'S OPERATING
COSTS FOR THOSE PROGRAMS AND VARIOUS OTHER FACTORS
INCLUDING WHETHER THE PROGRAM IS DESIGNATED FOR YOUTH SENIORS
OR PERSONS WITH DISABILITIES SUBJECT TO APPROVAL OF THE
RECREATION AND PARK COMMISSION DIRECTING THE COMMISSION TO
UPDATE ITS SCHOLARSHIP POLICY TO PROVIDE FOR FURTHER
DISCOUNTS FOR RECREATION PROGRAMS BASED ON FINANCIAL
NEED, MAKING CLARIFYING CHANGES AND AFFIRMING THE SECRET
DETERMINATION. ITEM 18 THIS ORDINANCE AMENDS
THE BUSINESS AND TAX REGULATIONS CODE THE HEALTH
CODE, THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE AND THE PUBLIC WORKS CODE TO
ELIMINATE THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH PERMIT
REQUIREMENT FOR VETERINARY HOSPITALS AND LAUNDRY
FACILITIES TO ELIMINATE THE FOOD FACILITIES SURCHARGE
AND CERTAIN FEES FOR AGRICULTURAL INSPECTIONS TO
ESTABLISH FEES FOR REGULATORY COMPLIANCE ACTIVITIES FOR SOLID
WASTE FACILITIES. REFUSE SERVICE FOR COMMERCIAL
AND RESIDENTIAL PROPERTIES AND LICENSING OF REFUSE
COLLECTORS, ESTABLISH REGULATORY FEE FOR FOOD SAFETY
CLASSES AND FOOD SAFETY EXAMINATIONS TO INCREASE
EXISTING REGULATORY FEES FOR AGRICULTURAL INSPECTION
AND HAZARDOUS WASTE MANAGEMENT TO INCREASE PENALTIES FOR
VIOLATIONS OF TOBACCO SALES ORDINANCE BY TOBACCO RETAILERS
AND TO DECREASE FEES FOR CERTIFIED FARMERS MARKET
PERMITS. ITEM 19 THIS ORDINANCE AMENDS
THE HEALTH CODE TO SET PATIENT RATES FOR SERVICES PROVIDED BY
THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH AND AUTHORIZED TO WAIVE OR
REDUCE FEES TO MEET THE NEEDS OF LOW INCOME PATIENTS THROUGH
ITS PROVISION OF CHARITY CARE AND OTHER DISCOUNTED PAYMENT
PROGRAMS. ITEM 20 THIS ORDINANCE AMENDS
THE PUBLIC WORKS AND SUBDIVISIONS CODE TO MODIFY
CERTAIN PERMIT FEES INCLUDING WAIVING FEES FOR CAFE TABLES
AND CHAIRS AND DISPLAY MERCHANDISE, REGISTRANTS
AND CERTAIN MINOR SIDEWALK ENCROACHMENTS THAT ARE A
PERTINENT BUILDING FEATURES AND AFFIRMS THE SECRET
DETERMINATION. ITEM 21 THIS RESOLUTION
APPROVES THE BUDGET OF THE OFFICE OF COMMUNITY INVESTMENT
AND INFRASTRUCTURE OPERATING AS THE SUCCESSOR AGENCY TO THE SAN
FRANCISCO REDEVELOPMENT AGENCY ALSO KNOWN AS OCI OR SUCCESSOR
AGENCY AND APPROVES THE ISSUANCE BY OCI OF BONDS IN AN
AGGREGATE PRINCIPAL AMOUNT NOT TO EXCEED 223 MILLION TO
FINANCE A PORTION OF OCI SIZE ENFORCEABLE OBLIGATIONS.
ITEM 22 THIS RESOLUTION AND CONCURS WITH THE
CONTROLLERS ESTABLISHMENT OF THE CONSUMER PRICE INDEX FOR
2025 AND ADJUST THE ACCESS LINE TAX BY THE SAME RATE ITEM 23
THIS RESOLUTION APPROVES THE HOMELESSNESS AND SUPPORTIVE
HOUSING FUND EXPENDITURE PLAN FOR THE DEPARTMENT OF
HOMELESSNESS AND SUPPORT OF HOUSING FUND ITEM 24.
THIS RESOLUTION AUTHORIZES THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC LIBRARY TO
ACCEPT AND EXPEND A 1 MILLION GRANT OF IN-KIND GIFTS SERVICES
AND CASH MONEYS FROM THE FRIENDS OF THE SAN FRANCISCO
PUBLIC LIBRARY FOR DIRECT SUPPORT FOR A VARIETY OF PUBLIC
PROGRAMS AND SERVICES. ITEM 25 THIS RESOLUTION CONCURS
WITH THE COMPTROLLER CERTIFICATION THAT DEPARTMENT
SERVICES PREVIOUSLY APPROVED CAN BE PERFORMED BY PRIVATE
CONTRACTOR FOR A LOWER COST THAN SIMILAR WORK PERFORMED BY
CITY EMPLOYEES FOR THE FOLLOWING SERVICES BUDGET
AND LEGISLATIVE ANALYST SERVICES FLEET SECURITY
SERVICES REAL ESTATE DIVISION. CUSTODIAL SERVICES.
REAL ESTATE DIVISION. SECURITY SERVICES CONVENTION
FACILITIES MANAGEMENT SECURITY SERVICES FOR THE GENERAL
SERVICES AGENCY. PUBLIC WORKS SECURITY SERVICES
SECURITY SERVICES FOR HOMELESSNESS AND SUPPORT OF
HOUSING HUMAN SERVICES AGENCY. FOOD SERVICES AT THE COUNTY
JAIL. THE ASSEMBLY OF VOTE BY MAIL
SERVICES AND SECURITY SERVICES FOR THE DEPARTMENT OF
ELECTIONS. >> THE MAYOR'S OFFICE OF
HOUSING AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT AND PUBLIC HEALTH
ITEM 26 THIS RESOLUTION AUTHORIZES THE RECREATION
AND PARKS DEPARTMENT TO ACCEPT AND EXPAND A 3.6 MILLION
BEQUEST FROM THE ESTATE OF WILLIAM BENJAMIN BOBO TO
PROVIDE BENCHES, PARK FURNISHINGS AND PARK
IMPROVEMENTS AT VARIOUS PARK SITES ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO.
ITEM 27 THIS RESOLUTION AUTHORIZES THE MUNICIPAL
TRANSPORTATION AGENCY TO SET PARKING RATES IN GOLDEN GATE
PARK AND TO AFFIRM THE SECRET DETERMINATION ITEMS 28 THROUGH
31 ARE FOR RESOLUTIONS THAT AUTHORIZE THREE ACCEPT
AND EXPEND GRANTS AND ONE GRANT AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE
DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH AND VARIOUS STATE ENTITIES.
ITEM 28 IS A REOCCURRING STATE GRANT FUNDS BY THE SAN
FRANCISCO DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH.
ITEM 29 IS A GRANT AGREEMENT FOR A TERM COMMENCING ON
EXECUTION ACTING THROUGH THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH
AND THE CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF SOCIAL SERVICES AND ITS
THIRD PARTY ADMINISTRATION HORN LLP UNDER THE COMMUNITY CARE
EXPANSION PROGRAM AND HAVING ANTICIPATED REVENUE TO THE CITY
OF APPROXIMATELY 9.9 MILLION FOR CONSTRUCTION OF A SUBSTANCE
USE DISORDER RESIDENTIAL STEPDOWN FACILITY AT PARCEL E1
POINT TWO TREASURE ISLAND. ITEM 30 THIS IS A RETROACTIVE
AUTHORIZATION FOR THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH TO
ACCEPT AND EXPEND 2.5 MILLION FROM THE CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT
OF HEALTH CARE SERVICES THROUGH THE SAN FRANCISCO HEALTH
AUTHORITY, A LOCAL GOVERNMENT ENTITY DOING BUSINESS AS THE
SAN FRANCISCO HEALTH PLAN. ITEM 31 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO
AUTHORIZE THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH TO EXPEND 6
MILLION THIS IS A GRANT FROM THE CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF
HEALTH CARE SERVICES AND THROUGH THE HEALTH PLAN TO
PARTICIPATE IN A PROGRAM IN ENTITLED INCENTIVE INCENTIVE
PAYMENT PROGRAM FOR THE EPIC ENHANCEMENT IMPLEMENTATION
PROJECT AND TO DELEGATE AUTHORITY UNDER CHARTER SECTION
9.11 SUB A TO THE DIRECTOR TO APPROVE GRANT AGREEMENT BETWEEN
THE CITY AND THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH.
AND FINALLY ITEM 32 THIS WAS REFERRED WITHOUT RECOMMENDATION
FROM THE BUDGET AND APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE
PURSUANT TO BUSINESS AND TAX REGULATIONS CODE SECTION 2811
AMENDMENTS OF THE ARTICLE 28 OF THE BUSINESS AND TAX
REGULATIONS CODE REQUIRE APPROVAL BY A SUPERMAJORITY
VOTE OF AT LEAST EIGHT MEMBERS TO APPROVE THIS ITEM.
ITEM 32 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AUTHORIZE THE CITY TO
REALLOCATE APPROXIMATELY 34.7 MILLION IN PRIOR APPROPRIATED
REVENUE OF UNAPPROPRIATED EARNED INTEREST WITHIN THE OUR
CITY. OUR HOME ALSO KNOWN AS OCHO
HOPE FUND TO FOLLOW TO ALLOW THE CITY TO USE REVENUES FROM
THE HOMELESSNESS GROSS RECEIPTS TAX FOR CERTAIN TYPES OF
SERVICES TO ADDRESS HOMELESSNESS NOTWITHSTANDING
THE EXPENDITURE PERCENTAGES SET FORTH IN THE BUSINESS AND TAX
REGULATIONS CODE WHERE FUTURE REVENUE AND INTEREST TO THE
FUND EXCEEDS AMOUNTS APPROPRIATED IN THE ADOPTED
BUDGET FOR FISCAL YEARS 2025 THROUGH 2626 AND 27 TO
AUTHORIZE THE CITY TO EXPEND UP TO 19.1 MILLION OF SUCH
ADDITIONAL REVENUES AND INTERESTS ON ANY PROGRAMS
TO ADDRESS HOMELESSNESS AS DESCRIBED IN THE BTR CODE
SECTION 2810 WITH REGARD TO EXPENDITURE PERCENTAGES IN THAT
SECTION AND TEMPORARILY SUSPENDING THE LIMIT ON FUNDING
FOR SHORT TERM RENTAL SUBSIDIES AND TO FIND THAT THESE
ALLOCATIONS ARE NECESSARY TO ACHIEVE THE PURPOSE OF THE OUR
CITY OUR HOME FUND PURSUANT TO THE BTR CODE SECTION 2811.
>> THANK THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK .
AS AS THE CLERK INDICATED, THE BUDGET HAS TO COME BACK TO THE
BOARD PER THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE BY JULY 15TH BUT THE
CHARTER REQUIRES THAT WE ARE NOT TO ADOPT THE BUDGET EARLIER
THAN JULY 15TH NOR LATER THAN AUGUST 1ST.
SO AT SOME POINT WE ARE GOING TO NEED TO CONTINUE THESE ITEMS
TO OUR NEXT BOARD MEETING ON JULY 15TH.
BUT BEFORE WE DO THAT SUPERVISORS CHAIR BUDGET CHAIR
CONNIE CHAN THANK YOU PRESENT AMENDMENT COLLEAGUES BEFORE WE
CONTINUE THESE ITEMS I WOULD LIKE TO MAKE TWO TECHNICAL
AMENDMENTS TO THE BOARD'S SUPERVISORS BUDGET SPENDING
PLAN. THESE AMENDMENTS SHOULD HAVE
BEEN PROVIDED TO YOU PREVIOUSLY.
>> THE FIRST IS TO INCLUDE THE REDUCTION TO THE DEPARTMENT OF
CHILDREN, YOUTH AND THEIR FAMILIES AND THIS WOULD
ACTUALLY ADD AN AGREEMENT TO SUBSTITUTE A BUDGET
AND LEGISLATIVE ANALYST'S RECOMMENDATIONS TO REDUCE THE
DEPARTMENT FUNDING. AND THIS IS WE CAME TO AN
AGREEMENT ABOUT DOWNWARD SUBSTITUTION OF A MANAGEMENT'S
POSITIONS AND ELIMINATE AN ADDITIONAL VACANCY TO ACHIEVE A
COMPARABLE COST SAVING AND THEN ALSO THIS AGREEMENT ALSO
INCLUDE THE ADDITIONAL NON JOURNAL FINAL REDUCTION OF
NEARLY $26,000 AND ALSO THE AMENDMENT IS ON TOP OF THE PAGE
OF THE SHEET THAT YOU HAVE IN FRONT OF YOU WHICH ADDED A
THIRD LINE UNDER THE DEPARTMENT BUDGET REDUCTION SECTION AT THE
TOP. THE SECOND AMENDMENT IS ON THE
SECOND SIDE OF THE DOCUMENTS TO UPDATE THE LANGUAGE FOR LINE
SIX REPLACING THE WORDS IN THE SIX AND THE 11 WITH WITH THE
LINE WITH THE LANGUAGE THAT IS QUOTE AND COMMUNITY
STABILIZATION AND CULTURAL DEVELOPMENT.
THIS LANGUAGE MORE ACCURATELY REFLECTS THE FULL DIVA
COMPLIMENTS OF SERVICE FOR RESTORATION AND I WOULD LIKE TO
MOVE THESE TWO AMENDMENTS. >> THERE IS A MOTION TO ON THE
FLOOR AND THERE IS A SECOND FROM SUPERVISOR WALTON AND I
THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT MOTION WITHOUT OBJECTION.
ALL RIGHT. THE MOTION PASSES.
AND THEN CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO CONTINUE THESE ITEMS WITH THE
AMENDMENT? WE JUST VOTED ON TO THE BOARD
MEETING OF JULY 15TH 2025 MOVED BY SUPERVISOR CHAN AND SECONDED
BY SUPERVISOR DORSEY. >> AND MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU
PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THE MOTION TO CONTINUE?
>> ITEM THREE THROUGH 34 AS AMENDED ITEMS THREE AND FOUR TO
JULY 15TH 2025 SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN
EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO
AND ENGARDIO EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER EYES SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISE RANDLEMAN RIGHT MANDEL MAN EYES
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SARDAR SADR EYES
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I AND SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON
EITHER ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE ITEMS ARE
CONTINUED TO JULY 15TH 2025 MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 33
ITEM 33 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE PARK CODE TO APPLY
THE PARK CODE TO CERTAIN PARKS ON TREASURE ISLAND AND YERBA
BUENA ISLAND TO ALLOW APPLICATION OF THE PARK CODE TO
CERTAIN ADDITIONAL PROPERTIES OPERATED AND MANAGED BY THE
RECREATION AND PARKS DEPARTMENT.
>> SUBJECT TO APPROVAL OF THE CREATION AND PARKED COMMISSION
AND TO MAKE CLARIFYING CHANGES LET'S TAKE THIS ITEM SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE
IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
34. >> ITEM 34 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE
TO AMEND THE PLANNING CODE TO UPDATE ELIGIBILITY REQUIREMENTS
FOR THE PRIORITY PROCESSING PROGRAM FOR CERTAIN COMMERCIAL
USES INCLUDING ENABLING FORMULA RETAIL USE WITH FEWER THAN 20
ESTABLISHMENTS TO PARTICIPATE IN THE PROGRAM AND UPDATING
SCHEDULING AND EXTENSION EXTENSION EXTENSION
REQUIREMENTS FOR THE PRIORITY PROCESSING PROGRAM TO AFFIRM
THE SECRET DETERMINATION AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> AND AGAIN SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 35.
>> ITEM 35 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE BUILDING
AND PLANNING CODES TO EXTEND THE AWNING AMNESTY PROGRAM TO
APPLY TO EXISTING UNPERMITTED SIGNS IN GATES TO AMEND THE
PLANNING CODE TO REMOVE DESIGN STANDARDS FOR GATES RAILINGS
AND GRILL WORK ON THE GROUND FLOOR.
STREET FRONTAGES OF NON HISTORIC BUILDINGS
IN NEIGHBORHOOD COMMERCIAL RESIDENTIAL, COMMERCIAL,
COMMERCIAL AND MIXED USE DISTRICTS TO AFFIRM THE SECRET
DETERMINATION AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS
PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 36.
ITEM 36 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE PLANNING CODE TO
STREAMLINE AND SIMPLIFY THE PROCESS FOR OBTAINING
AND EXTENDING TEMPORARY USE AUTHORIZATIONS IMPLEMENT
STANDARDS REQUIREMENTS FOR ANY TEMPORARY USE AUTHORIZATION
AND PERMIT AS TEMPORARY USES SEASONAL POLITICAL CAMPAIGN
OFFICES FOR UP TO ONE YEAR TO EXTEND THE MAXIMUM TIME FOR A
POP UP RETAIL TEMPORARY USE TO THREE YEARS AND TO AFFIRM THE
SECRET DETERMINATION AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE
IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 37
ITEM 37 ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE PUBLIC WORKS CODE TO STREAMLINE
THE APPROVAL OF CERTAIN ENCROACHMENTS IN THE PUBLIC
RIGHT OF WAY TO ESTABLISH A REGISTRATION REQUIREMENT
IN PLACE OF ALL PERMIT REQUIREMENTS AND FEES FOR CAFE
TABLES AND CHAIRS AND DISPLAY MERCHANDISE AND TO ELIMINATE
MINOR ENCROACHMENT PERMIT REQUIREMENTS AND RIGHT OF WAY
OCCUPANCY FEES FOR A PERMANENT BUILDING FEATURES TO AMEND THE
ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO EXEMPT CAFE TABLES AND CHAIRS
AND DISPLAY MERCHANDISE FROM THE SHARED SPACES PROGRAM
AND TO AFFIRM THE SECRET DETERMINATION AND SAME HOUSE
SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE
IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
38. >> ITEM 38 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE
TO AMEND THE POLICE CODE TO ADJUST VARIOUS ENTERTAINMENT
FEES AND WE CAN DO THAT SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING
AND MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO OUR 2:30 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER
RECOGNITION OF COMMENDATIONS YES THE RECOGNITION OF
COMMENDATIONS FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY
OF SAN FRANCISCO. >> ALL RIGHT, SAM MORGAN, COME
FORWARD. I AM VERY EXCITED TODAY
COLLEAGUES, TO BE ABLE TO PRESENT A SPECIAL COMMENDATION
TO SAM MORGAN. I'M A NATIVE SAN FRANCISCAN
SECOND GENERATION GROCER AND VISIONARY BEHIND THE BAY
RIGHT FAMILY OF BUSINESSES SAM'S FAMILY HAS OWNED BY RITE
MARKET ON 18TH STREET SINCE 1964.
HE GREW UP WORKING IN THE MARKET BUT LATER CHOSE TO
PURSUE A DIFFERENT CAREER PATH AFTER HIGH SCHOOL HE GRADUATED
FROM SAN FRANCISCO CITY COLLEGE AS HOTEL AND RESTAURANT
MANAGEMENT PROGRAM THEN COOKED IN SWITZERLAND AND OAKLAND
BEFORE OPENING HIS OWN RESTAURANT RENDEZVOUS DEMAND
IN 1991. >> IN 1997 SAM AND HIS BROTHER
TOOK OVER BY RITE MARKET. THE NEXT YEAR THE TWO
REINVENTED THE FAMILY BUSINESS THROUGH A CHEF'S PERSPECTIVE.
THEY BUILT OUT THE KITCHEN TO ALLOW SAM TO CONTINUE COOKING
INGREDIENTS STOCKED FROM LOCAL FARMERS.
SINCE THEN, SAM HAS OVERSEEN THE EXPANSION OF BAY RIGHT
ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO. THEY OPENED A SECOND BY RIGHT
MARKET ON TO VISIT ARROW BRIGHT CREAMERY JUST UP THE STREET
FROM THE 18TH STREET MARKET AND A COMMISSARY AND CATERING
KITCHEN IN THE BAYVIEW. I LAUNCHED A SHOPPING APP
AND MOST RECENTLY CELEBRATED THE OPENING OF THEIR THIRD
BRIGHT MARKET LOCATION ON POLK STREET.
AND THOSE ARE JUST A FEW OF THE BRIGHT PROJECTS THAT HAVE KEPT
SAM BUSY THESE LAST THREE DECADES.
DURING THAT TIME HE ALSO HELPED FOUND 18 REASONS A NONPROFIT
COMMUNITY COOKING SCHOOL THAT EMPOWERS THOUSANDS OF RESIDENTS
EACH YEAR WITH THE SKILLS AND CONFIDENCE TO COOK
AND SHARE NOURISHING MEALS. >> SAM'S COMMITMENT TO
SUSTAINABILITY AND EQUITY IS REFLECTED IN BRIGHT
CERTIFICATION AS A B CORP AND ITS RECOGNITION AS A BEST
FOR THE WORLD HONOREE FOR COMMUNITY IMPACT.
HIS LEADERSHIP HAS HELPED SHAPE SAN FRANCISCO'S FOOD CULTURE
MAKING IT MORE INCLUSIVE, ETHICAL AND DELICIOUS.
AS A PROUD PALESTINIAN-AMERICAN SAM AGIM EXEMPLIFIES THE
ENTREPRENEURIAL SPIRIT AND CIVIC DEDICATION THAT
ARAB-AMERICANS HAVE BROUGHT TO SAN FRANCISCO FOR GENERATIONS.
HIS WORK HAS NOT ONLY ENRICHED OUR CITY'S CULINARY LANDSCAPE
BUT ALSO STRENGTHENED THE SOCIAL FABRIC OF OUR
COMMUNITIES. >> SAM YOU ARE AN EXTRAORDINARY
HUMAN BEING. YOUR BASIC KINDNESS AND DECENCY
ARE BREATHTAKING, AS ARE YOUR ACCOMPLISHMENTS.
SO TODAY WE HONOR YOU FOR YOUR AMAZING CONTRIBUTIONS TO SAN
FRANCISCO'S FOOD CULTURE AND COMMUNITY AND FOR BEING A
GREAT SAN FRANCISCAN. AND I HAVE COLLEAGUES WHO ALSO
WANT TO SAY NICE THINGS ABOUT YOU SO YOU CAN'T SPEAK YET.
>> SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD. >> SAM, I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
FOR THREE THINGS IN ADDITION TO WHAT PRESIDENT BENJAMIN SAID.
ONE BEARD ISN'T JUST A GROCERY STORE BUT IT'S A VISION FOR HOW
YOU THINK ABOUT EQUITY WITHIN COMMUNITIES.
AND I'VE SEEN HOW YOU'VE COLLABORATED WITH BOOKER T
WASHINGTON ON FOOD ACCESS AND THAT HAS BEEN REALLY
AMAZING TO SEE IN DISTRICT FIVE.
SECOND IS I'VE BEEN NOT SURE YOU'RE ALLOWED TO ANNOUNCE IT
YET BUT YOUR YOUR NEW NONPROFIT GROCERY STORE I THINK IS A
REALLY BRILLIANT MODEL THAT I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO SEEING IT
TAKE OFF AND JUST SHOWS HOW MUCH YOU CARE ABOUT DOING
THINGS DIFFERENTLY, DOING THINGS EQUITABLY AND MAKING
SURE THAT THERE ARE DIFFERENT MODELS FOR FOOD ACCESS
AND YOU'RE DOING IT AT A NOT FOR PROFIT.
SO IT'S PRETTY AMAZING TO SEE. AND THIRD IS AS SOMEONE WITH A
REALLY BAD SWEET TOOTH, YOU HAVE SOME OF THE BEST ICE CREAM
IN THE CITY AND HOPE YOU CAN GET MORE OF THOSE THROUGHOUT
THE CITIES AS WELL. >> SO THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR SUPERVISOR FIELDER A
NEIGHBOR. >> THANKS, PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN
INDEED AS A NEIGHBOR BY RIGHT TAKES MORE OF MY MONEY THAN I
THINK MY BUDGET WOULD WOULD ALLOW.
>> BUT I JUST WANTED TO TO SAY THAT SAM EXEMPLIFIES WHAT IT
MEANS TO BE A SAN FRANCISCAN AND THAT THE PROSPERITY THAT
YOU GENERATE YOU ALSO DEDICATE YOURSELF TO SHARING WITH THE
REST OF SAN FRANCISCANS. AND THAT MEANS A WHOLE LOT TO A
LOT OF PEOPLE NOT JUST MYSELF BUT A LOT OF PEOPLE THAT SHARE
THAT VALUE AS WELL. IN SAN FRANCISCO.
SO THANK YOU SO MUCH. IT'S BEEN GREAT TO BECOME YOUR
FRIEND IN THIS POSITION AND I JUST APPRECIATE YOU SO MUCH.
>> SUPERVISOR CHAN THANK YOU. >> IT SEEMS LIKE I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU REMEMBER SAM WE WENT WAY BACK IN TERMS OF JUST HOW
COMMITTED YOU ARE TO THE COMMUNITY AND WHEN DOLORES PARK
THROUGH MY WORK AT REGEN PARK THAT THERE WAS A LOT OF
CHALLENGES WITH BROKEN GLASSES ALL OVER THE PARK AND WHEN THE
DEPARTMENT WENT TO YOU AND SAY WELL WE KNOW THAT WHERE PEOPLE
ARE BUYING THEIR BEERS AND CHAMPAGNE GLASSES AND AND
WINE AND ALCOHOL AND IMMEDIATELY YOU'RE
COMMITTED TO MAKING SURE THAT THE PARK STAYS SAFE AND THAT
ENVIRONMENTAL FRIENDLY AND THAT YOU'RE COMMITTED TO ACTUALLY
CHANGE YOUR EVENTS THREE TO CANS AND REALLY THINK ABOUT
LIKE HOW DO YOU CONTRIBUTE TO THE TO THE CITY AND TO YOUR
PARKS AND OPEN SPACES AND TO FAMILIES BY REALLY WE KNOW THAT
IT'S A COST TO DOING THE BUSINESS AND YET YOU WERE
COMMITTED TO DO THAT. I KNOW THAT ON SO MANY LEVELS
YOU DID THAT YOU MAKE SURE THAT YOU CAN OPEN A SOFT SERVE LIKE
BUSINESS INCLUDING SOFT SERVE THAT IT'S AFFORDABLE TO THE
NEIGHBORHOOD ACROSS THE STREET THE CIVIC CENTER PLAZA WHEN IT
FIRST GOT GOING. JUST ALL OF THAT.
SAM, THANK YOU. AND THEN I DON'T THINK IT'S
JUST THE PAST GENERATION BUT THE FUTURE GENERATION OF SAN
FRANCISCANS REALLY ARE LUCKY TO HAVE YOU AS ONE OF US.
THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU.
SO I HOPE THAT WE'VE APPROPRIATELY EMBARRASSED YOU
AND NOW THE FLOOR IS YOURS. WELL, YOU KNOW, I'M SUPER
GRATEFUL TO YOU ALL AND HONORED THAT THAT YOU'VE MADE THIS MADE
THE TIME FOR ME AND TO RECOGNIZE THE WORK THAT NOT
JUST I DO BUT MY PARTNER CALVIN TSAI AND MY ENTIRE TEAM DOES.
>> IT'S A IT'S A IT'S A COLLABORATIVE EFFORT AND WE
WOULDN'T BE ABLE TO DO IT WITHOUT THE SUPPORT OF THE
ENTIRE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND ALL THE COMMUNITIES THAT WE
THAT WE SUPPORT AND WORK WITH. YOU KNOW, I'M I'M A NATIVE SAN
FRANCISCO AND I LOVE THIS CITY AND AND I FEEL THAT BUSINESSES
HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY TO BE PARTNERS AND TO BE MORE THAN
PRIVATE ENTERPRISES, THAT THEY HAVE A PUBLIC PURPOSE AND THAT
PURPOSE SHOULD BE TO UPLIFT AND TO RECOGNIZE THOSE THAT
IN ALL OF OUR COMMUNITIES THAT NEED LOVE AND SUPPORT.
AND IT'S SOMETHING THAT I LEARNED FROM MY FATHER AT A
VERY YOUNG AGE THAT ANY TIME HE WHEN I WAS WORKING IN THE STORE
WITH HIM, ANY TIME THAT ANYONE THAT CAME INTO THE STORE THAT
WAS HUNGRY HE WOULD ASK ME TO MAKE A SANDWICH FOR THEM
AND FEED THEM. AND THAT I THINK IS ONE THING
ONE THING THAT EVERY BUSINESS THAT DOES BUSINESS IN SAN
FRANCISCO SHOULD UNDERSTAND THAT THEY HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY
BEYOND MAKING A PROFIT. AND I THINK THAT THAT'S ONE OF
THE THINGS THAT THAT HAS MADE BY RIGHT DIFFERENT AND HAS
BROUGHT US HERE TODAY ANYWAY. SO I'M I'M GRATEFUL AND YOU
KNOW SUPERVISOR MOHAMOUD I'M EXCITED ABOUT THE THE NONPROFIT
GROCERY STORE TOO. I THINK YOU KNOW, WE'VE MADE
SOME GREAT STRIDES FORWARD IN THE LAST FEW WEEKS.
I THINK WE'VE GOT THE RIGHT SUPPORT IN ORDER TO BE ABLE TO
PUSH IT FORWARD. SUPERVISOR WALTON, I LOOK
FORWARD TO TALKING TO YOU ABOUT IT SOON.
IT'S IT'S SLATED TO HAPPEN IN THE IN THE SUNNYDALE ACROSS
THE STREET FROM THE HUB AND I'M ALSO VERY EXCITED TO TO SEE
WHAT AND HOPEFULLY MAYORAL CANDIDATE MAMDANI IN NEW YORK
CITY ACTUALLY GETS ELECTED AND AND GETS TO REALIZE HIS
VISION OF CREATING STATUS AND YOU KNOW PUBLICLY SUPPORTED
GROCERY STORES IN EACH OF THE BOROUGHS IN MANHATTAN SO THAT
WE CAN BEGIN TO SEE A MODEL WHERE GOOD FOOD IS ACCESSIBLE
TO MORE PEOPLE BECAUSE EVERY EVERY CITIZEN OF THIS OF THIS
COUNTRY DESERVES TO BE ABLE TO EAT EVERY DAY THERE THERE ARE
FAR TOO MANY PEOPLE THAT ARE HUNGRY, ESPECIALLY CHILDREN
AND IT'S IT'S INCUMBENT UPON ALL OF US AS LEADERS EVERY
SINGLE ONE OF US IS A LEADER TO DO OUR PART IN MAKING SURE THAT
WE FEED PEOPLE AND TAKE CARE OF EACH OTHER BECAUSE WE AT THE
END OF THE DAY WE NEED EACH OTHER IN ORDER TO BE ABLE TO
GET THROUGH EVERYTHING THAT'S COMING AT US EVERY DAY.
SO I APPRECIATE YOU ALL. >> THANK YOU SO THANK YOU ALL.
THANK YOU ALL RIGHT. AND WITH THAT I THINK WE GO TO
THE COMMITTEE REPORTS ITEMS 41 AND 42 WERE CONSIDERED BY THE
RULES COMMITTEE AT A REGULAR MEETING ON MONDAY, JULY 7TH
AND THEY WERE RECOMMENDED AS AMENDED BEARING NEW TITLES FOR
ITEM 41. THE AMENDMENT IS TO STRIKE THE
WORD REJECTING IT NOW READS MOTION TO APPROVE PRESIDENT
RAFAEL MENDELSSOHN'S NOMINATION FOR THE APPOINTMENT OF GAIL
STARR TERM ENDING JUNE 6TH, 2029 TO THE ENHANCED
INFRASTRUCTURE FINANCING DISTRICT PUBLIC FINANCING
AUTHORITY NUMBER ONE. SIMILARLY ITEM 42 STRIKES THE
WORD REJECTING IT NOW READS MOTION TO APPROVE MOTION
APPROVING PRESIDENT RAFAEL MANDEL MEANS NOMINATION FOR THE
APPOINTMENT OF KENNETH SOKOLOFF.
HIS TERM ENDING JUNE 6TH, 2027 TO THE ENHANCED INFRASTRUCTURE
FINANCING DISTRICT PUBLIC FINANCING AUTHORITY NUMBER ONE.
ALL RIGHT. I THINK WE CAN TAKE THESE ITEMS
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTIONS ARE
APPROVED. >> AND MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO
ROLLCALL FIRST MEMBER TO INTRODUCE NEW BUSINESS.
HIS SUPERVISOR CHAN SUBMIT. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHEN
SUBMIT. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR DORSEY
SUBMIT THANK YOU SUPERVISOR AND GAUDIO SUBMIT THANK YOU
SUPERVISOR FIELDER SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MENDELSOHN SUBMIT SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MELGAR SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR SAUTER OKAY, I'M
GOING TO INTERRUPT THAT. WHAT I'M SORRY MADE I PROMISE
IT'S FOR A GOOD REASON. SO COLLEAGUES TODAY I AM
CALLING FOR A HEARING ON THE CURRENT PERFORMANCE AND FUTURE
EXTENSION OF THE CENTRAL SUBWAY.
AS YOU KNOW THE CENTRAL SUBWAY HAS BEEN OPEN SINCE NOVEMBER
2022 AND THIS FOLLOWED MORE THAN TWO DECADES OF PLANNING
AND COMMUNITY ADVOCACY PARTICULARLY FROM THE CHINATOWN
COMMUNITY. AND I THINK IT'S NOW TIME TO
EXAMINE WHAT IS WORKING WHERE WE'VE FALLEN SHORT AND WHAT'S
NEXT. SO OUR HEARING WILL SEEK TO
ADDRESS THE FOLLOWING FIRST TO EXAMINE THE CURRENT PERFORMANCE
OF THE CENTRAL SUBWAY. WE HAVE A LOT TO LEARN FROM THE
MANY MISTAKES AND DELAYS IN GETTING IT OPEN OF COURSE,
BUT I BELIEVE THERE'S ALSO PROMISING NUMBERS FOR US TO
HIGHLIGHT. >> FOR EXAMPLE APRIL AND MAY OF
THIS YEAR SET CONSECUTIVE RECORDS FOR HIGHEST RIDERSHIP
MONTHS EVER AND 2025 THE CLOSURE DATES WITHSTANDING SHOW
A 15% YEAR OVER YEAR RIDERSHIP GROWTH ON THE LINE.
>> NEXT I EXPECT OUR HEARING TO PRODUCE A SET OF SPECIFIC SHORT
TERM IMPROVEMENTS THAT S.F. MTA WILL COMMIT TO THAT WILL
DELIVER CONCRETE IMPROVEMENTS TO SPEED RELIABILITY
AND OPERATIONS OF THE SUBWAY. WE WANT TO LEARN MORE ABOUT THE
OPPORTUNITIES TO SPEED UP THE TRAIN AT BOTTLENECKS THROUGHOUT
THE SYSTEM. FOUR AS QUICKLY AS THE TRAIN
MOVES UNDERGROUND. WE'VE ALL BEEN IN THAT
UNFORTUNATE SITUATION WHEN WE ARE ABOVE GROUND AND SEE
PEDESTRIANS ON THE SIDEWALK WALKING FASTER THAN WE MOVE ON
THE TRAIN. >> WE ALSO EXPECT COMMITMENTS
ON HOW THE CHINATOWN ROSE PARK STATION WILL AVOID CONTINUED
BREAKDOWNS OF ITS ELEVATORS AND ESCALATORS THAT FORCE
SENIORS TO CLIMB HUNDREDS OF STAIRS.
AND WE WANT DETAILS ON WHEN THE EMPTY RETAIL KIOSKS IN UNION
SQUARE IN CHINATOWN WILL OPEN. FINALLY, OUR HEARING SHOULD
ADDRESS THE OUTLOOK AND SPECIFIC NEXT STEPS FOR AN
EXTENSION OF THE CENTRAL SUBWAY TO NORTH BEACH AND FISHERMAN'S
WHARF. WE'VE ALREADY STUDIED THIS
EXTENSION FOR MORE THAN A DECADE.
A 2014 CITY STUDY SHOWED A TWO STATION EXTENSION WOULD LIKELY
BOOST RIDERSHIP BY 55%. >> WE ALSO KNOW THAT THIS
EXTENSION WOULD COMPETE FAVORABLY FOR FEDERAL FUNDING
WHEN SUCH FUNDING IS AVAILABLE TO SAN FRANCISCO AGAIN.
LET'S GET READY NOW SO WE CAN MAKE THE CASE FOR HOW IMPORTANT
THIS EXTENSION IS AND WE CAN WIN THESE FUNDS IN THE NEAR
FUTURE. AND LET'S REMEMBER THE CENTRAL
SUBWAY TUNNEL IS ALREADY DUG ALL THE WAY TO NORTH BEACH.
SINCE 2014, FOR MORE THAN TEN YEARS NOW AN EMPTY TUNNEL HAS
BEEN SITTING UNDER TENS OF THOUSANDS OF RESIDENTS IN ONE
OF THE COUNTRY'S DENSEST NEIGHBORHOODS.
I CALL FOR THIS HEARING WITH FULL AWARENESS THAT WE ARE
IN THE MIDST OF A FINANCIAL CRISIS FOR OUR TRANSIT SYSTEMS
HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO AND NATIONWIDE.
>> WE CAN AND MUST KEEP OUR FOCUS SQUARELY ON FINDING MORE
SUSTAINABLE FUNDING, IMPROVING OPERATIONS AND AVOIDING A
LOOMING FISCAL CLIFF. BUT WE ALSO NEED TO GIVE OUR
TRANSIT RIDERS SOMETHING TO BELIEVE IN.
WE MUST SHOW THAT OUR SYSTEM IS ALWAYS STRIVING TO BE BETTER
AND DELIVER A WORLD CLASS TRANSIT SERVICE THAT WE ALL
DESERVE. >> THIS IS WHAT OUR VOTERS
AND RESIDENTS OF SAN FRANCISCO NEED.
IF WE ARE TO PASS FUTURE FUNDING MEASURES AND IN THIS
CASE WE MUST FINALLY REACH THE FULL PROMISE OF THE CENTRAL
SUBWAY PROJECT. BECAUSE DELAYS AND ENDLESS
STUDIES WITH NO FOLLOW UPS HAVE CONSEQUENCE THIS PLENTY OF PAST
MISTAKES HAVE GOTTEN US TO THE SITUATION TODAY BUT WE CANNOT
ALLOW OUR GENERATION IN THIS BOARD TO MAKE THOSE SAME
MISTAKES. I WAS REMINDED OF THIS RECENTLY
WHEN I READ AN OP ED FROM TOMMY, A 16 YEAR OLD HIGH
SCHOOL STUDENT AT JEWISH COMMUNITY HIGH SCHOOL OF THE
BAY WHO CALLED FOR THAT EXTENSION AND A WONDERFUL OP
ED. AND I'M REMINDED OF THIS EVERY
TIME I LOOK AT MY DAUGHTER NOW THREE MONTHS OLD AND WONDER HOW
OLD SHE WILL BE WHEN SHE CAN RIDE THE CENTRAL SUBWAY AS IT
WAS MEANT TO BE. >> IT'S NOT TOO MUCH TO ASK FOR
THE DENSEST NEIGHBORHOODS IN SAN FRANCISCO WITH SOME OF
THE LOWEST CAR OWNERSHIP RATES IN THE ENTIRE COUNTRY.
TO HAVE ACCESS TO A SUBWAY I LOOK FORWARD TO OUR HEARING TO
SHOW HOW WE CAN FINALLY DELIVER THIS AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR SAUTER .
SUPERVISOR CHERYL SMITH SUBMIT. THANK YOU AND SUPERVISOR WALTON
SUBMIT. THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> SEEING NO NAMES ON THE ROSTER, THAT CONCLUDES THE
INTRODUCTION OF NEW BUSINESS. THANK YOU MADAM CLERK.
I REALIZE I MAY HAVE SHOUTED AT THE WRONG PERSON A SUBCOMMITTEE
DID T V TODAY SO IF JAMES COHEN IS OUT THERE HELPING US I WANT
TO THANK JAMES KAWANA AND WITH THAT WE CAN DO 14 MINUTES OF
PUBLIC COMMENTS SO WE ARE GOING TO DO A FIRST ROUND OF PUBLIC
COMMENT. >> IF WE ARE NOT FINISHED WE'LL
COME BACK TO IT LATER. THANK YOU MR. PRESIDENT.
SO IF YOU'LL LINE UP ON YOUR RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER
NEXT TO THE CURTAINS YOU PUBLIC COMMENT YOU ARE ABLE TO SPEAK
ON THE MAYORAL APPEARANCE. YOU'RE ABLE TO SPEAK ON WHETHER
OR NOT THE BOARD SHOULD GO INTO CLOSED SESSION ON THE P, G
AND E LITIGATION THAT IS ITEM OF 445 AND YOU CAN SPEAK TO
ITEMS 40 SIX THROUGH 50. >> THOSE ARE ON THE ADOPTION
WITHOUT REFERENCE TO COMMITTEE. >> I'LL REPEAT AGAIN YOU MAY
NOT SPEAK TO THE BUDGET ITEMS AS THOSE ITEMS HAVE ALREADY HAD
THEIR PUBLIC COMMENT AND WE'LL HEAR FROM OUR FIRST SPEAKER
WELCOME MR. PHIL SO YOU LOOK THERE YOU SEE SHE WANTED TO
COME BECAUSE TWO OTHER BROTHERS CAME LAST YEAR WAS FOR DUTCH
WAS I MEAN HERE YES I GUESS THE FIVE SONS SO SEE I TOLD YOU
ANGELO LOOKS LIKE YOU I MEAN HE LOOK LIKE HER A LITTLE BIT BUT
TELL YOU THAT YEAH, I MEAN APART FROM THE HEY, I HAVE IT.
LOOK, YOU DON'T GET ANY IT'S ALL LIGHTS HERE TODAY, OKAY?
FOR THE KIDS. SEE NOW SHE HEARS EVERYTHING SO
SHE HEARD YOU DON'T WANT TO SPEAK, RIGHT?
NO, SHE DOESN'T WANT TO SPEAK BECAUSE FIRST UP SHE DOESN'T
SPEAK ENGLISH VERY WELL. >> NO.
>> OKAY. SO ANYWAY, SHE HEARS THE TRUTH.
YOU KNOW SHE UNDERSTANDS EVERYTHING SO YOU CAN'T HIDE
AND DOESN'T WATCH. SO SOONER OR LATER YOU SEE
BECAUSE THE KIDS KNOW TOO THEY ARE THERE.
>> THIS COULD BEAUTIFUL I SHOULD SAY BUT IT'S FOR THE
KIDS. >> SO ANYWAY, I DON'T HAVE
ANYTHING MUCH MORE IMPORTANT TO SAY TODAY.
>> I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT ENOUGH WHAT?
IT'S YEAH, EVERYTHING MATTERS. REMEMBER THIS ONE?
EVERYTHING THING MATTERS. >> EVERYTHING THEY JUST AN
ORDER OF IMPORTANCE I THINK WE AGREE HERE WE HAVE A GOOD TO
YOU TO MAYOR ALL BY THE WAY IT'S A LOT OF YOUR RESOLUTIONS
YOU PASS TODAY I GET WELL HANG ON GUYS I HAVE A GOOD DAY ON A
MAYBE I SEE YOU NEXT WEEK THAT YOU GO THANK YOU CAN WE HEAR
FROM OUR NEXT SPEAKER PLEASE WELCOME.
HELLO MY NAME IS LIAM MCKEEVER. >> I LIVE IN D SIX I AM REALLY
CONFUSED ABOUT SAN FRANCISCO'S IMMIGRANT SANCTUARY STATUS.
>> I HAVE BEEN GOING OVER TO ICE COURT ON A WEEKLY BASIS
AND FIGHTING WITH ICE. >> THERE'S LIKE THESE CLASHES
BETWEEN ICE AND PEOPLE THAT DON'T WANT PEOPLE ABDUCTED
AND DEPORTED TO SOUTH SUDAN OR SOME CONCENTRATION CAMP
IN SOUTH AMERICA OR ALCATRAZ OR ALLIGATOR ALCATRAZ.
THE CONFRONTATION INS ARE GETTING MORE AND MORE VIOLENT
EVERY TIME PEOPLE ARE LIKE BEING RAMMED INTO BY THESE ICE
VEHICLES SOMEONE IS GOING TO GET HURT TODAY I WAS ASKING
SFPD WHAT THEIR ROLE IS HERE BECAUSE THEY STAND BY THEY
CLEAR THE ROAD FOR ICE OPERATIONS.
THEY LET THE VANS WITH THE ABDUCTED PEOPLE, MAKE SURE THEY
CAN GO THROUGH THE CITY. >> THEY SAY THEY'RE NOT
FACILITATING AN ICE OPERATION AND I TELL YOU IT VERY MUCH
FEELS LIKE FROM MY POINT OF VIEW THEY ARE SO CAN YOU PLEASE
DO YOUR JOB? >> CAN YOU CAN YOU DEFINE WHAT
THIS SANCTUARY STATUS ACTUALLY IS AND THEN ENFORCE IT?
YOU KNOW, I'M REALLY GLAD I HAVE MY WIFE WHO IS A
TRANSGENDER WOMAN BECAUSE I JUST DON'T GET MAD ON MY OWN
BEHALF ANYMORE WHEN THESE DOUBLE STANDARDS ARE HELD FOR
CIVILITY, HOW I'M SUPPOSED TO TALK TO YOU AFTER WITNESSING
WHAT I DO EARLIER TODAY WITH AND ICE AND MY PEOPLE BEING
ABDUCTED YOU KNOW SHE STILL GETS MAD ON MY BEHALF.
SHE GETS MAD AT THE DOUBLE STANDARDS HERE AND SHE GETS MAD
THAT WHITE MEN CAN CALL ME A VERY OFFENSIVE SLUR REPEATEDLY
DIRECT HIS COMMENT AT ME WHILE I'M SITTING BACK HERE WITH THE
PUBLIC AND THAT'S NOT GIVEN AS MUCH RECOMMENDATION AS I AM
GIVEN FOR SAYING THE F-WORD. >> I JUST TELL HER IT'S A STATE
OF BEING TRANS IN AMERICA A TRANS MEXICAN-AMERICAN AT THE
MOMENT. THANK YOU LIAM MCKEEVER FOR
YOUR COMMENTS. CAN WE HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER? PLEASE WELCOME MISS BROWN.
COME HERE. YOU'RE NOT DOING ANYTHING.
>> JUST STAND OVER HERE. >> COME IN THE MIRROR.
OKAY. I'M HERE TODAY WITH MY
GRANDCHILDREN. I MEAN IN A MIRROR.
THEY'RE TWINS AND I'M HERE TO, YOU KNOW, TALK ABOUT THEIR
THEIR THEIR THEIR UNCLE THAT PASSED AWAY NEXT MONTH WILL BE
THE I MEAN AUGUST 14TH WILL BE THE ANNIVERSARY OF HIS MURDER
AND I'VE BEEN COMING TO THESE CHAMBERS AND THE POLICE
COMMISSION FOR YEARS. IT'LL BE 20 YEARS THIS YEAR
AND MY TWO GRANDCHILDREN ARE GROWING UP WITHOUT THEIR UNCLE.
I HAVE 12 GRANDCHILDREN THAT DON'T HAVE AN UNCLE TO LOOK UP
TO. I ASKED THAT ON THE ANNIVERSARY
OF HIS DEATH THAT YOU THAT MOST OF YOU WOULD SHOW UP ON GROVE
STREET TO REPRESENT UNSOLVED HOMICIDES TO BRING AWARENESS TO
ALL THE UNSOLVED HOMICIDES TO HELP MOTHERS LIKE MYSELF.
I DO APPRECIATE THAT THAT'S NEW.
THE POLICY THAT THAT'S BEEN PASSED ABOUT WAYS TO PAY
TIPSTERS HAVE BEEN PASSED. I'M PRAYING THAT THE MAYOR COME
AND SIGN THAT POLICY SO THAT HE CAN, YOU KNOW, LET THE MOTHERS
KNOW THAT HE DO CARE. >> SO I'M PRAYING THAT HE WILL
COME AND SIGN THAT POLICY WITH US AND HAVE US AT LEAST STAND
WITH HIM. AND I THANK YOU, MATT DARCY FOR
FOUR FOR A MONTH FOR DOING THIS FOR US AND PLEASE DON'T STOP
WORKING FOR US. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. ALL RIGHT.
LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
>> >> HELLO, MY NAME IS JASON WYMAN.
I HAVE LIVED ON THE CORNER OF 20TH AND HAMPSHIRE FOR OVER 20
YEARS. >> IN THAT COURSE OF THE TIME
THAT'S BEEN DISTRICT 6 TO 16 AND NOW DISTRICT NINE.
AND I WANT TO SPEAK TO WHAT I HEARD AS THE PRIORITIES OF SAN
FRANCISCO FROM THE MAYOR TODAY. >> WHAT I HEARD WAS PUBLIC
SAFETY, CLEAN STREETS AND STRONG RECOVERY IN MY
EXPERIENCE WORKING IN THIS CITY AND IN THIS TOWN IT SEEMS LIKE
THOSE ACTUALLY AREN'T THE COMMITMENTS CURRENTLY
ESPECIALLY GIVEN THE STATE OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> WHAT SEEMS TO BE THE COMMITMENTS OF SAN FRANCISCO
ARE RENEGING ON COMMITMENTS AND SLASHING BUDGETS VERY
SPECIFICALLY FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO DREAM KEEPER
INITIATIVE FUNDING. THAT WAS A COMMITMENT MADE BY
THE CITY THAT IT RENEGED ON. >> IT ALSO SEEMS TO BE A
PRIORITY THAT WE ARE PRIVATIZING EVERYTHING.
>> I JUST RECENTLY FOUND OUT THAT WE'RE GOING TO BE CHARGING
FOR PARKING IN GOLDEN GATE PARK.
>> WHAT ARE WE DOING? DO WE NOT HAVE ANY FREE
RESOURCES IN THIS CITY OR THE THIRD THING THAT I WANT TO TALK
ABOUT SPECIFICALLY YES. >> WHAT IS YOUR TIME JUST FOR A
MOMENT YOUR TIME IS PAUSED. THE BUDGET MATTERS THAT I READ
OFF EARLIER. >> I HEAR YOU.
THESE ARE PRIORITIES OF SAN FRANCISCO NOT JUST FUNDING
PRIORITIES OF SAN FRANCISCO. >> BEGIN YOUR TIME.
THANK YOU. THREE SECONDS LEFT.
THE THIRD PRIORITY THAT I KEEP HEARING ABOUT IS PUBLIC SAFETY
. >> ON JULY THE 4TH I CAN TELL
YOU THAT RIGHT OUTSIDE MY HOME THERE WAS A MILITARIZED POLICE
PRESENCE. THEY CAME DOWN BOTH SIDES OF
HAMPSHIRE STREET AND THEY CAME DOWN 20TH STREET IN FORMATION
WITH THE BATONS AT THEIR READY. THEY MADE THREATS TO THE
COMMUNITY THAT WAS SETTING OFF SOME FIREWORKS RIGHT THERE ON
20TH THAT HAVE BEEN DOING IT FOR OVER 20 YEARS.
AGAIN, I HAVE LIVED THERE FOR OVER 20 YEARS.
IT IS A REGULAR OCCURRENCE EVERY SINGLE YEAR.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN S.F. PD IN MILITARY FORMATION MARCHED
ON THE STREET, ISSUE COMMANDS AND TELL MY NEIGHBORS THAT IF
ANYONE WERE TO LAY HANDS ON A POLICE VEHICLE THEY WOULD BE
MET WITH ASSAULT. THAT WAS STATED BY S.F. PD ON
JULY THE FOURTH. THAT IS NOT PUBLIC SAFETY.
THAT IS PUBLIC TERROR AND THAT IS PUBLIC TERROR AS WE CONTINUE
TO SEE ICE SHOW UP IN SAN FRANCISCO.
SO AGAIN, IT SEEMS TO ME THAT THE MAYOR'S PRIORITIES ARE NOT
ACTUALLY THEIR RHETORICAL PRIORITIES.
THEY ARE NOT ACTUAL PRIORITIES OF THE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO
AND IT'S REALLY DISAPPOINTING. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER
AND WE'RE PROBABLY ONLY GOING TO BE ABLE TO TAKE 1 OR 2 MORE
FOLKS BEFORE OUR 3 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER.
>> THANK YOU AND THEN WE'LL COME BACK LATER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS APPLE.
I'M A RESIDENT OF DISTRICT SEVEN AND I'M SPEAKING FROM
LIVED EXPERIENCE OVER TEN YEARS UNHOUSED ON THE STREETS OF SAN
FRANCISCO AND YOU'RE STRUGGLING WITH SUBSTANCE USE.
I'M HERE TO STRONGLY OPPOSE MAYOR THE MAYOR'S BREAKING THE
CYCLE INITIATIVE AND THE PROPOSAL TO RE ALLOCATE
PROPERLY FUNDS AWAY FROM THEIR ORIGINAL PURPOSE PROPERTY WAS
PASSED BY VOTERS WITH A CLEAR MANDATE TO FUND PERMANENT
HOUSING, VOLUNTARY MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES AND HARM
REDUCTION NOT INVOLUNTARY TREATMENT OR CARE SCHOOL
SYSTEMS REDIRECTING 90 MILLION UNSPENT PROP C FUNDS TO
BREAKING THE CYCLE WITHOUT MEANINGFUL COMMUNITY
ENGAGEMENT. >> MA'AM, I'M PAUSING YOUR TIME
. THAT MATTER IS ASSOCIATED WITH
THE BUDGET THAT WE HAVE CONTINUED TO NEXT WEEK.
IT HAS ALREADY HAD ITS PUBLIC COMMENT SO I CAN'T I CAN'T
FINISH MOMENT IF YOU WANT TO TELL US ABOUT YOUR EXPERIENCE.
HAPPY TO TAKE THAT BUT DON'T TALK ABOUT ITEM 32 ON THE
AGENDA. THAT'S THE PROP C THAT YOU WERE
REFERRING TO. >> OKAY.
I CAN SPEAK FROM MY OWN EXPERIENCE.
>> I'LL RESUME YOUR TIME. THANK YOU.
WHILE I CAN'T SPEAK FOR EVERYBODY BECAUSE EVERY CRISIS
IS DIFFERENT, I CAN'T SPEAK FOR MY EXPERIENCE AT 16 YEARS OLD I
WAS FORCED INTO A LOCKED MENTAL HEALTH FACILITY FOR NEARLY A
YEAR. IT WAS TRAUMATIC.
I WAS CONSERVED, HELD AGAINST MY WILL AND DENIED DIGNITY
AND AUTONOMY OVER MY OWN LIFE. IT DIDN'T BREAK THE CYCLE FOR
ME. IT DEEPENED IT AND SPIRALED ME
FURTHER INTO CRISIS POVERTY AND ADDICTION FOR YEARS.
IF THE CYCLE IS JAILS, HOSPITALS AND BEING BACK TO THE
STREETS I LIVED THAT WHAT FINALLY BROKE THE CYCLE FOR ME
WASN'T FORCE IT WAS LOW BARRIER VOLUNTARY CARE AND ACCESS TO
PERMANENT HOUSING. >> SO PLEASE REJECT THIS
REALLOCATION. >> THANK YOU.
SO IF THERE ARE ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC WHO ARE
IN LINE THAT EXPECT TO TALK ABOUT ITEM 32 OR PROPOSITION C
,THAT IS NOT ALLOWED. I WILL BE REDIRECTING YOU AS
WELL. >> WELCOME.
THANK YOU. WHAT OF SUPERVISOR MEMBERS
TODAY? I JUST WANT TO REITERATE A
QUOTE THAT'S SAID EVERY TIME THAT WE GO THROUGH BUDGET
ISSUES IN THIS CITY IS SHOW ME YOUR BUDGET AND I'LL SHOW YOU
WHAT YOU CARE ABOUT. AND BY THAT MEASURE, SAN
FRANCISCO'S VALUES ARE LOUD AND CLEAR AND DEEPLY
DISAPPOINTING FOR THE BLACK COMMUNITY.
THE LARGEST DIVESTMENT IN THIS YEAR'S CITY BUDGET HAS COME AT
THE DIRECT EXPENSE OF BLACK SAN FRANCISCANS PROGRAMS CREATED TO
UPLIFT, STABILIZE AND EMPOWER COMMUNITIES PARTICULARLY AND D
TEN AND D FIVE HAVE BEEN QUIETLY DEFUNDED OR
DEPRIORITIZED AND THE SAME RESIDENTS WHO HAVE HAD LONG
CARRIED THE WEIGHT OF THE SYSTEMIC INEQUALITY WERE
EXCLUDED FROM MEANINGFUL BUDGET CONVERSATIONS UNTIL AFTER THE
DECISIONS BY THIS BOARD HAD HARDLY BEEN MADE AS WELL AS THE
MAYOR. >> THIS STANDS IN DIRECT
CONTRADICTION TO THE PUBLIC COMMITMENTS MADE JUST A FEW
YEARS AGO. MOST OF THE MEMBERS OF THIS
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS MARCHED IN THE STREETS DURING THE
GEORGE FLOYD UPRISINGS WITH MANY OTHER COMMUNITY MEMBERS.
MANY STOOD BESIDE COMMUNITY, RAISED FISTS WITH US
AND PUBLICLY PLEDGED TO REIMAGINE PUBLIC SAFETY
AND INVEST IN BLACK COMMUNITIES.
THOSE ACTIONS MATTERED BUT THEY MUST BE BACKED BY POLICY
FUNDING AND FOLLOW THROUGH. WE ARE HERE TODAY ASKING THIS
BOARD TO UPHOLD THAT PROMISE. THE BLACK COMMUNITY DEMANDS THE
FOLLOWING ACTIONS A CITYWIDE AUDIT OF THE DREAM KEEPERS
INITIATIVE AND WE CALL FOR A FULL AND TRANSPARENT AUDIT.
ALLOCATE OUT OF EVERY SINGLE DOLLAR THAT HAS BEEN ALLOCATED
TO EVERY CITY DEPARTMENT IN THE CITY SINCE THE PROGRAM'S LAUNCH
INCLUDING HOW MUCH WAS ACTUALLY SPENT ON THE BLACK COMMUNITIES
AND HOW MUCH WENT TO INTERMEDIARIES, NON-BLACK LED
ORGANIZATIONS AND REMAINED UNSPENT.
WE ALSO ARE REQUESTING A FULL ACCOUNTING OF UNPAID INVOICES
OWED TO BLACK LED ORGANIZATIONS AS WELL AS A FULL RESCINDING
AND REISSUE OF THE CURRENT HRC RFP 100.
WE CALL FOR THE IMMEDIATE CANCELLATION AND RE ISSUANCE OF
THE RFP DUE TO LACK OF CLARITY AND TRANSPARENCY IN THE PROCESS
. CONTRADICTORY
AND DISCRIMINATORY EVALUATION AND LANGUAGE WITHIN THE RFP AS
WELL AS A MEASURABLE REVERSAL OF THAT THAT THAT BASICALLY
GIVES A MEASURABLE REVERSAL OF PROGRESS EMERGING FROM BLACK.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS .
SO I THINK WE WILL COME BACK TO PUBLIC COMMENT AFTER OUR 3 P.M.
SPECIAL ORDER. >> SO WE WILL RESUME PUBLIC
COMMENT BUT IT WILL BE IN A BIT OF TIME.
MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE CALL OUR 3 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER?
>> YES, THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WILL CONVENE AS A
COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE. THIS IS SCHEDULED PURSUANT TO A
RESOLUTION NUMBER 208 DASH 25 ADOPTED ON MAY 6TH, 2025 FOR A
PUBLIC HEARING OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TODAY TO CONSIDER
RENEWAL AND EXPANSION OF A PROPERTY BASED BUSINESS
IMPROVEMENT DISTRICT KNOWN AS THE OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY
BENEFIT DISTRICT. ITEM 40 IS THE RESOLUTION THAT
ESTABLISHES THE PROPERTY BASED BUSINESS IMPROVEMENT DISTRICT.
AGAIN KNOWN AS THE OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT TWO
ORDER THE LEVY AND COLLECTION OF ASSESSMENTS AGAINST PROPERTY
LOCATED WITHIN THE DISTRICT FOR THE NEXT 15 YEARS COMMENCING
WITH FISCAL YEAR 20 2526 SUBJECT TO CONDITIONS AS
SPECIFIED IN TO MAKE THE ENVIRONMENTAL FINDINGS.
THANK YOU MADAM CLERK. THE PURPOSE OF THIS COMMITTEE
OF THE WHOLE IS TO HEAR TESTIMONY ON THE PROPOSED LEVY
OF ASSESSMENTS ON THE PROPERTY AND BUSINESS IMPROVEMENT
DISTRICT NAMED OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT.
PURSUANT TO THE BOARD'S RESOLUTION OF ITS INTENTION
ADOPTED MAY 6TH, 2025, THE RESOLUTION OF INTENTION TO
RENEW AND EXPAND THIS DISTRICT SCHEDULED TODAY'S HEARING
AND ALSO APPROVED THE MANAGEMENT DISTRICT PLAN.
THE ENGINEER'S REPORT EACH DATED APRIL 2025 AND THE FORM
OF BALLOTS FOR THE PROPERTY OWNERS.
I AM ANTICIPATING THAT AT TODAY'S HEARING SUPERVISOR CHEN
WILL INTRODUCE PROPOSED AMENDMENTS TO THE MANAGEMENT
PLAN AND ENGINEER'S REPORT EACH DATED JULY 2025 AND ALSO
INCLUDED IN YOUR FILE. AND I AM ALSO ANTICIPATING THAT
THE AMENDMENT ITSELF WILL BE DETAILED LATER BY SUPERVISOR
CHEN. >> AFTER THE PUBLIC HEARING IS
CLOSED AND THE AMENDMENT IS CONSIDERED.
THE DEPARTMENT OF ELECTIONS WILL COUNT ALL BALLOTS
SUBMITTED INCLUDING ANY ADDITIONAL BALLOTS RECEIVED
DURING THE BUSINESS HEARING. THE BUSINESS HEARING TODAY
AND SUBMIT THE TABULATION TO THE BOARD.
MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC MAY VIEW THE BALLOT TABULATION BY THE
DEPARTMENT OF ELECTIONS ON THE BASEMENT LEVEL OF CITY HALL
IN ROOM 59. IF THE TABULATION OF THE
WEIGHTED BALLOTS SHOWS A MAJORITY PROTEST, THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS WILL NOT APPROVE THE ESTABLISHMENT OF THE
DISTRICT OR IMPOSE THE ASSESSMENTS.
IF THERE IS NOT A MAJORITY PROTEST THEN THE BOARD MAY VOTE
TO ESTABLISH THE DISTRICT AND IMPOSE THE ASSESSMENTS.
A MAJORITY PROTEST WILL EXIST IF THE WEIGHTED BALLOTS ARE
SUBMITTED IN OPPOSITION TO THE ESTABLISHMENT OF THE ASSESSMENT
DISTRICT EXCEED THE WEIGHTED BALLOTS SUBMITTED IN FAVOR OF
ESTABLISHMENT OF THE ASSESSMENT DISTRICT.
BALLOTS ARE WEIGHTED ACCORDING TO THE PROPOSED FINANCIAL
OBLIGATION OF EACH AFFECTED PROPERTY AND AFTER THE HEARING
CLOSES THE BALLOTS WILL BE COUNTED.
SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU PRESIDENT AND I DO HAVE A MEMO
THAT I'M GOING TO INTRODUCE MY COLLEAGUES TODAY.
I DO REALLY SINCERE HOPE THAT YOU ALL WILL SUPPORT THE
RENEWAL OF THE OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT.
>> THE OLD AA HAS HELPED TO MAKE THIS COMMERCIAL CORRIDOR A
MORE THRIVING AND BEAUTIFUL SPACE FOR BOTH DISTRICT SEVEN
AND DISTRICT 11 RESIDENTS THROUGH ALWAYS LEADERSHIP THEY
HAVE CONTINUED TO ADD NEW MURALS PROVIDE INTENSIVE
PRESSURE WASHING AND CLEANING AND ORGANIZE COMMUNITY EVENTS
AND PROVIDE TECHNICAL ASSISTANCE TO SMALL BUSINESS.
>> MOST RECENTLY I HAVE ENJOYED AT A WINE TASTING EVENT THAT
AND ALSO A VERY POPULAR BOBA FESTIVAL AND TAO FUN WHICH THIS
YEAR WE CONNECTED THE EXCELSIOR CORRIDOR TO OCEAN AVENUE
BUSINESS AS WELL. DURING THE HEARING I PLAN TO
INTRODUCE AGAIN THE AMENDMENT TO AMEND THE COMMUNITY BENEFIT
DISTRICTS DISTRICTS BOUNDARIES. >> THE AMENDMENT WILL ALSO
REMOVE SOME NON COMMERCIAL PARCELS AT THE END OF THE
DISTRICT. >> I ALSO WANT TO THANK
AND ALSO RECOGNIZE THE SUPERVISOR MAL GUSS LEADERSHIP
AND ALSO HER STAFF JEN ALL FOR THE HOT WEATHER TO MOVE THIS
FORWARD TO HELP OUR SMALL BUSINESS AND I ALSO WANT TO
THANK THE ENGINEER AND JACKIE HAZELWOOD FROM O W D FOR THEIR
CONTINUED PARTNERSHIP AND COLLABORATION AND I
APPRECIATE THE WORK BOTH OF YOU HAVE DONE TO GET THE AMENDMENTS
IN TIME FOR TODAY'S HEARING. >> I REALLY APPRECIATE JACKIE
HAS ALWAYS MAKE HERSELF AVAILABLE AND ALSO TO WORK WE
MY MY STAFF IN SHOUTING THANK YOU JACQUI.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHEN
SUPERVISOR MELGAR THANK YOU SO MUCH PRESIDENT MANDELL.
MAN I ALSO WANT TO THANK THE STAFF PARTICULARLY JACKIE
HAZELWOOD FROM EWG FOR HER DILIGENCE AND ATTENTION.
I WANT TO RECOGNIZE THE WORK THE GREAT WORK OF FORMER
SUPERVISOR JOHN AVALOS AND ALSO SUPERVISOR LS BERND WHO GOT
THIS TO WHERE IT NEEDED TO BE ORIGINALLY AND AS A SUPERVISOR
CHEN AND I HAVE WORKED TOGETHER OVER THE LAST SIX MONTHS I HAVE
TO RECOGNIZE HOW IMPORTANT IT IS TO HAVE THIS INTER DISTRICT
COLLABORATION FOR A COMMERCIAL CORRIDOR SUCH AS OCEAN AVENUE
WHICH SERVES BOTH DISTRICTS AND I CANNOT EXPRESS HOW
IMPORTANT THIS COMMUNITY BENEFITS DISTRICT HAS BEEN TO
OUR MERCHANT CORRIDOR TO OUR TO MY CONSTITUENTS AND SUPERVISOR
CHEN'S CONSTITUENTS AND I KNOW THAT SHE WILL BE INTRODUCING
SOME AMENDMENT WHICH I WHOLEHEARTEDLY SUPPORT OVER THE
COURSE OF THE LIFE OF THIS COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT.
THE CHANGE ON OCEAN AVENUE HAS BEEN NOTICEABLE.
I HAVE LIVED IN THIS COMMUNITY FOR ABOUT 15 YEARS AND SINCE
THE SPEED SEABEDS INCEPTION I CAN SEE THERE'S REGULAR
SWEEPING GRAFFITI REMOVAL STREET WASHING AND AT THE VERY
FRIENDLY PRESENCE OF OUR CORRIDOR AMBASSADOR ROLLAND WHO
ALWAYS HAS A SMILE AND IS THERE TO GREET NEIGHBORS AND THEN THE
LITTLE TOUCHES LIKE THE FLOWER BASKETS THAT ARE HANGING THE
NEW MURALS, THE FRIENDLY FACES ON THE STREET AS WE EXPAND THE
SERVICES UNDER THIS RENEWAL I KNOW THAT THE CBD WILL NEED TO
STRENGTHEN ITS OWN CAPACITY. WE WILL BE THERE TO SUPPORT YOU
AND TO MAKE SURE THAT IT IS A FUNCTIONING ORGANIZATION THAT
THRIVES AND IS CONNECTED TO THE COMMUNITY AND ADDRESSES THE
DIVERSITY OF THE MANY BUSINESSES IN THIS CORRIDOR.
IT'S WHAT MAKES OUR COMMUNITY SO WONDERFUL.
IT HAS BEEN A JOURNEY TO GET TO THIS PLACE TODAY I FEEL
CONFIDENT THAT THE NEXT CHAPTER OF THE OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION
WILL BE BRIGHT. I ESPECIALLY WANT TO THANK
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR KRISTA MARTIN AND ROSENDO AS WELL.
THANK YOU FOR ALL THE WORK THAT YOU DO.
YOU THANK YOU FOR TAKING THIS ORGANIZATION IN A POSITIVE
DIRECTION. I WILL VOTE TODAY ALSO BECAUSE
WE'RE PROPOSING TO EXPAND THE CBD FURTHER INTO DISTRICT SEVEN
COVERING LAKESIDE VILLAGE WHICH IS THE OTHER SIDE OF OCEAN
AVENUE. LAKESIDE VILLAGE IS ON THE
UPSWING BECAUSE OF THE VISIONARY SUPPORT FROM
COMMUNITY LEADERS AND NEIGHBORS AND I PARTICULARLY WANT TO
SHOUT OUT TO KAZAKH ALASKANS WHO WE ACTUALLY JUST VOTED INTO
THE FIVE D COMMITTEE AND IN THE FRIENDS OF LATE SITE VILLAGE
WHO WANT TO REVIVE THIS OFTEN FORGOTTEN PART OF THE
COMMERCIAL CORRIDOR. SO I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO
SEEING IT BE A PART OF THE CBD STRENGTHENING OCEAN AVENUE,
GETTING ALL THOSE GOOD NEIGHBORS ENERGY INTO WHAT
WE'RE TRYING TO DO. I HOPE COLLEAGUES THAT WE CAN
SUPPORT THIS EFFORT TODAY AND CONTINUE ALL OF THE GOOD
WORK THAT HAS BEEN DONE BY THIS ORGANIZATION AND THE STAFF
IN DISTRICTS 11 AND SEVEN THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR MILLER I BELIEVE
THAT WE HAVE PRESENTED PATIENCE.
>> YES. COME ON UP.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH. SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS JACKIE HAZELWOOD AND THE COMMUNITY BENEFIT
DISTRICT PROGRAM DIRECTOR WITH THE OFFICE OF ECONOMIC
AND WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT. I'M PART OF THE TEAM THAT
OVERSEES AND ADMINISTERS THE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT
PROGRAM ON BEHALF OF BWT. >> SO I'M JOINED HERE TODAY BY
CASSIO HOLLICK FROM OUR CBD TEAM AT IWD AS STATED IN THE
RESOLUTION ITSELF THIS IS A RENEWAL AND EXPANSION OF THE
EXISTING OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT ALSO KNOWN AS
THE OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION AND I TOUCHED UPON
IN SUPERVISOR CHEN'S OPENING REMARKS THERE WILL ALSO BE A
FORTHCOMING AMENDMENT FROM THE SUPERVISOR THAT WOULD EXCLUDE
54 PARCELS FROM THE INITIALLY PROPOSED BOUNDARIES AND I'LL
SOON INTRODUCE CHRISTIAN MARTIN, EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF
THE OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION. BUT BEFORE I DO I WANT TO
ACKNOWLEDGE AND THANK SEVERAL PEOPLE A MASSIVE THANK YOU TO
SUPERVISOR MELGAR FOR HER ONGOING SUPPORT OF THE
ORGANIZATION FOR THE EFFORTS WITH RENEWAL AND BEYOND
AND BEFORE THANK YOU ALSO TO YOUR STAFF.
THANK YOU PARTICULARLY TO JEN LOW AND THANK YOU ALSO TO
SUPERVISOR CHEN. THANK YOU TO YOUR STAFF
LUNCHEON. THANK YOU FOR ALL YOUR SUPPORT
AND WORKING TO GET TO A RESOLUTION HERE.
>> I'D ALSO LIKE TO COMMEND EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR CHRISTIAN
MARTIN HIS STAFF AND ALWAYS BOARD OF DIRECTORS FOR THEIR
ONGOING EFFORTS THROUGHOUT THIS CAMPAIGN.
IT'S CERTAINLY BEEN A MARATHON AND NOT A SPRINT.
CHRISTIAN AND HIS TEAM IT'S MEANINGFUL WORK ON THIS RENEWAL
LAYS THE GROUNDWORK FOR CONTINUED SUCCESS AS THE
ORGANIZATION LOOKS AHEAD TO THE POSSIBILITY OF CONTINUING THEIR
WORK FOR ANOTHER 15 YEARS AS A PART OF THIS RENEWAL THE OCEAN
AVENUE ASSOCIATION IS PROPOSING TO EXPAND ITS BOUNDARIES TO
INCLUDE THE LAKESIDE VILLAGE COMMERCIAL CORRIDOR LEADING
THIS EXPANSION TO THE LAKESIDE VILLAGE IS KATH SUCKLE ORCAS
CO-FOUNDER OF FRIENDS OF LAKESIDE VILLAGE, A NONPROFIT
FORMALIZED IN 2020 BUT WORKING FOR YEARS EVEN BEFORE THAT TO
ENSURE THAT COMMERCIAL CORRIDOR IS CLEAN AND VIBRANT CASTS
ABILITY TO CONNECT TO EVERYONE CONNECT WITH EVERYONE FROM
PROPERTY OWNERS TO MERCHANTS TO RESIDENTS HAS BEEN ESSENTIAL
IN BRINGING LAKESIDE VILLAGE INTO THE CONVERSATION HERE SO
THANK YOU KATH. >> LASTLY THIS PROCESS COULD
NOT BE COMPLETED WITHOUT VARIOUS CITY DEPARTMENTS
AND STAFF IN PARTICULAR I'D LIKE TO THANK CHRIS GORGEOUS
AND CASEY HOLLICK FROM OUR IWD STAFF FROM THE CLERK'S OFFICE
IN PARTICULAR LISA SAMARA AND JOHN CARROLL CREIGHTON ALSO
DEPUTY CITY ATTORNEY MONU PRADHAN AND FROM THE DEPARTMENT
OF ELECTIONS ALICE LAW AND PRISCILLA TOV.
>> SO NOW I'M GOING TO GO AHEAD AND INTRODUCE CHRISTIAN MARTIN,
THE EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION TO PROVIDE A
LITTLE BIT MORE DETAIL ON THE RENEWAL AND EXPANSION
AND SERVICES THAT ARE GOING BE A PART OF THAT.
WE'RE JUST GOING TO GET THE PRESENTATION SET UP.
THANK YOU. TAKE ALL GOOD AFTERNOON
SUPERVISORS. IT'S GOOD TO SEE MANY OF YOU.
THANK YOU ALL FOR THE OPPORTUNITY TO PRESENT.
I'D LIKE TO ECHO MANY OF JACKIE'S THANKS TO SUPERVISOR
MELGAR SUPERVISOR CHEN AND STAFF FOR ALL THE SUPPORT
OVER THE LAST COUPLE OF YEARS WE CERTAINLY WOULDN'T BE HERE
WITHOUT YOU AND YOU KNOW WE WE AIM TO KEEP THE COMMUNITY
THRIVING AND MOVING FORWARD SO COULDN'T DO WITHOUT YOU
APPRECIATE YOU WANT TO TALK A LITTLE BIT ABOUT WHERE WE HAVE
BEEN AND WHERE WE'RE GOING WITH THIS RENEWAL AND I WILL START
WITH A LITTLE HISTORY ABOUT THE OSA ESTABLISHED IN 2010 AND TO
DO CLEANING MAINTENANCE AND BUSINESS SUPPORT ON THE
CORRIDOR AND I STARTED IN 2023 FOLLOWING THE STRATEGIC PLAN
THAT THE ORGANIZATION ENACTED IN ORDER TO IMPROVE OUR OUR
BOARD RELATIONS AND OUR COMMUNITY RELATIONS AS WELL AS
OUR OPERATIONS. SO FOLLOWING THE SPRING AUDIT
WE ADDRESSED ALL OF THE FINDINGS GETTING OUR FISCAL
HOUSE IN ORDER, PUTTING BEST PRACTICES IN FOR ACCOUNTS
PAYABLE AND RECEIVABLE AND INCREASING TRANSPARENT AC
AND OPENNESS IN OUR OPERATING PROCEDURES.
AND I'M HAPPY TO REPORT THAT THAT AUDIT WAS CLOSED IN 2024
AND WE ADDRESSED ALL 19 FINDINGS OF WHICH ENABLED US TO
FOCUS MORE ON THE FUN STUFF WHICH IS A DIZZYING ARRAY OF
COMMUNITY EVENTS, BEAUTIFICATION PROJECTS
AND ENHANCED CLEANING AND MAINTENANCE PROGRAM THAT
PROVIDES DAILY SWEEPING WEEKLY PRESSURE WASHING LANDSCAPING,
OTHER BEAUTIFICATION PROJECTS ON THE CORRIDOR THAT MAKES THE
THE AVENUE FEEL CLEAN AND CARED FOR DAY IN AND DAY OUT.
SO BY THE NUMBERS WE COMPLETED 43,547 TASKS ALONG THE MAIN
OCEAN AVENUE CORRIDOR NOT COUNTING LAKESIDE VILLAGE.
THIS HAS BEEN DONE PREDOMINANTLY BY OUR ONE FULL
TIME AMBASSADOR ROLAND WHO SUPERVISES AND MELGAR SHOUTED
OUT EARLIER HE'S THE REAL MVP HERE DAY IN, DAY OUT DOING THE
DIRTY WORK. AND THEN MOST RECENTLY WE
ADOPTED THE LAKESIDE VILLAGE CORRIDOR COMPLETING 2650 TASKS
ALONG LAKESIDE VILLAGE FUNDED BY A GRANT THAT ALLOWS FOR
ROLAND TO GO DOWN THERE THREE DAYS A WEEK.
IN ADDITION THAT WORK COLLECTED ABOUT 62,025 POUNDS OF TRASH
WHICH IS ANYTHING FROM, YOU KNOW, LITTER TO TRASH THAT FELL
OUT OF WASTE RECEPTACLES RECOLOGY CANS THINGS LEFT
BEHIND BY THE UNHOUSED COMMUNITY YOU NAME IT
AND FECES, NEEDLES ALL THE HAZARDOUS WASTE AS WELL.
SO THAT'S MIXED IN WITH ALL OF THAT.
>> AND WE HAVE A SMALL TEAM OF LANDSCAPERS THAT COMES OUT ONCE
A WEEK DOING LIKE WEEDING TREE WELL CLEAN UP USING 311 CUTTING
LOW HANGING TREES COLLECTING LITTER AS WELL FILLING UP TRASH
BAGS, PLANTING TREES AND SWEEPING UP ANY LEAVES OR
DEBRIS THAT MAY HAVE ACCUMULATED.
SO WE'VE DONE OVER ALMOST 2000 LANDSCAPING TASKS BETWEEN OCEAN
AVENUE AND LAKESIDE VILLAGE OVER THE PAST COUPLE OF YEARS.
MOVING ON TO COMMUNITY EVENTS WE PROMOTED, SPONSORED OR
PARTICIPATED IN SEVERAL EVENTS CULTURAL CELEBRATIONS,
NETWORKING EVENTS, WINE WALKS, AN AWESOME BOBA FESTIVAL
BUSINESS NETWORKING EVENTS, ART SHOWS AND YOUTH EVENTS.
WE ALSO OPENED OUR OFFICE AT 1720 OCEAN AVENUE WHICH HAS
BEEN THE EPICENTER OF COMMUNITY ACTIVITY.
SO WE'VE DONE FITNESS SEMINARS, WELLNESS DAYS OBVIOUSLY HOSTING
OUR COMMUNITY MEETINGS AND BOARD MEETINGS THERE.
IT ALSO SERVES AS A PART TIME ART GALLERY AND EVENT SPACE.
SO THANKS TO ROSENDO AND GABE FOR KEEPING THAT SPACE ACTIVE
AND COMMUNITY SERVING AND THEN FINALLY THROUGH RESEND THOSE
WORK WITH THE CPD GRANT WE'VE DONE A NUMBER OF ADVOCACY
AND BUSINESS SUPPORT ACTIVITIES INCLUDING PROVIDING INFORMATION
AND ASSISTANCE ON GRANTS AND TAX CREDITS, TECHNICAL
BUSINESS SUPPORT AND PROMOTIONS .
SO WE TALK A LITTLE BIT ABOUT OUR CURRENT BUDGET WHICH IS
FROM THE ASSESSMENT ABOUT $378,000 BUT WE SUPPLEMENT THAT
WITH GRANTS AND EARNED INCOME. BUT IT IS A SHOESTRING BUDGET
AND IT'S REMARKABLE WHAT WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO DO.
BUT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT EXPANDING THAT AND INCLUDING
THE LAKESIDE VILLAGE PORTION. SO THE NEXT SLIDE WILL SHOW
WHAT WE'RE PROPOSING ON THE BALLOT AND THEN I'LL TALK A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT A SUPERVISOR CHANGE AMENDMENT.
>> SO OUR CURRENT BUDGET PROPOSED EXCUSE ME PROPOSED
BUDGET IN SERVICE AREA WOULD GIVE US A TOTAL BUDGET OF ABOUT
$500,000. AND WITH SUPERVISOR CHEN'S
AMENDMENT AND THE NEXT SLIDE YOU'LL SEE A LITTLE BIT TAKEN
OUT OF THE GENEVA AREA WHICH IS ABOUT 40 OR SO PARCELS AND THAT
WOULD BRING OUR BUDGET DOWN TO $460,000 WHICH WE ARE PREPARED
TO WORK WITH. SO LOOKING AHEAD WHAT WE ARE
PROPOSING IS EXPENSE EXPANDING THE DISTRICT TO LAKESIDE
VILLAGE EXPANDING A LITTLE BIT OUR AMBASSADOR SERVICE COVERAGE
TO DO A LITTLE BIT MORE CLEANING AND MAINTENANCE
AND CONTINUING OUR BUSINESS SUPPORT WITH ONE FULL TIME
AMBASSADOR AND TO FULL TIME EMPLOYEES DOING THE OFFICE TYPE
OF WORK. SO WITH THAT I AM HAPPY TO TAKE
ANY QUESTIONS. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU. I DO NOT SEE ANY QUESTIONS SO
IT MAY BE TIME FOR US TO GO TO PUBLIC COMMENT.
MADAM CLERK LET'S OPEN TO PUBLIC COMMENT FOR THE HEARING.
EVERY SPEAKER WILL BE ALLOTTED TWO MINUTES.
>> LET'S HEAR FROM OUR FIRST SPEAKER SO I LEAVE HIM THAT
AREA. CAN YOU GRAB THAT MICROPHONE
AND SPEAK DIRECTLY INTO IT? OKAY SO I'M HERE.
SORRY. NICE TO SEE YOU EVERYONE I LIVE
AND 18 DORADO TERRACE FOR FROM 2000 THE 11TH.
FIRST OF ALL I SEE THAT OCEAN AVENUE BE DOING A NICE JOB I
SEE CHANGES IT'S REALLY NICE SO I STOP BY BY OFFICE TALK TO
RONALD SO I'M KIND OF AROUND THAT AREA AND WALK A LOT WITH
MY DOG. >> WHAT I WANT TO MENTION
ANOTHER PART SOMEHOW I AM REPRESENTED KIND OF
REPRESENTATIVE OF ABOUT THREE RESIDENTIAL HOUSES THAT NOT ON
OCEAN AVENUE. SOMEHOW WE WERE INCLUDED INTO
BUSINESSES AND ASSESSMENT ASSESSMENT WHICH WILL GO TO
BUSINESSES ALSO SOMEHOW WE WILL GO TO JUST A FEW RESIDENTIAL
PROPERTIES WHEN THEY SEE IN THE IN MY WINDOW I SEE OTHER HOUSES
THAT NOT INCLUDED BUT EVEN THERE CLOSER TO OCEAN AVENUE
THAN MY HOUSE SO I AM READY TO PAY FOR THE ASSESSMENT BUT I
CANNOT UNDERSTAND WHY JUST LIMIT THAT NUMBER OF HOUSES
RESIDENTIAL HOUSES INCLUDED AND OTHER NOT INCLUDED SO IT
SHOULD BE EXTENDED WHO WILL PAY ASSESSMENT OR SHOULD BE OUR
HOUSE AS BE EXCLUDED. >> SO HERE'S MY POINT YOU THINK
YOU THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENT CAN WE HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER PLEASE? >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
AN ELECTED MEMBERS OF THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS GERALDINE ANDERSON. I'M A DEDICATED VETERAN CITY
AND COUNTY EMPLOYEE FOR OVER 36 YEARS OF SERVICE.
I'M THE AUTHOR OF TWO EMAILS WRITTEN TO CHAIRWOMAN OF THE
BUDGET AND FINANCE COMMITTEE SUPERVISOR CHAN AND THE SHARED
EMAIL TO MAYOR LURIE AND THE REST OF THE BOARD.
I RESPECTFULLY COME BEFORE YOU TODAY ON BEHALF OF THE MOST
SENIOR STAFF 42 EMPLOYEES TO BE EXACT OF THE SAN FRANCISCO
SUPERIOR COURT WHOSE EMPLOYMENT, TENURE
AND RETIREMENT BENEFITS ARE MONITORING.
>> I'M I'M GOING TO PAUSE YOUR TIME.
THIS IS NOT GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
FOR ALL OF YOU WHO ARE STANDING IN LINE, THIS IS A PUBLIC
HEARING FOR THE OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT
RENEWAL AND EXPANSION. I'M SO SORRY ONLY.
GREAT. THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE WILL RETURN TO PUBLIC COMMENT FOR GENERAL PUBLIC
COMMENT AT THE END OF THE WEEK LATER ON ON THIS AFTERNOON.
>> LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
WELCOME. >> GOOD AFTERNOON BOARD.
MY NAME IS KATE FERRETTI. I HAVE LIVED IN THE BROADER OR
MY AREA FOR A LONG TIME MOST OF MY LIFE ALMOST THE ENTIRE POINT
OF MY LIFE. I AM AN INTERESTED MEMBER OF
THE COMMUNITY AND ALSO VERY ACTIVE IN THE COMMUNITY.
I AM HERE TO SPEAK STRONGLY IN FAVOR OF THE RENEWAL.
OCEAN AVENUE IS NOT JUST A COMMERCIAL CORRIDOR.
IT IS THAT ENTITY THAT KNITS OUR VERY DIVERSE COMMUNITIES
TOGETHER. AND AS THE OCEAN AVENUE
ASSOCIATION HAS BROUGHT FORTH NOT ONLY CLEANING AND GRAFFITI
REMOVAL AND THE INFRASTRUCTURE TYPE OF THINGS BUT IT'S THE
COMMUNITY BUILDING THAT AGAIN ACCENTUATES THAT BRINGING OUR
DIVERSE COMMUNITIES TOGETHER. WHAT IS ALSO VERY IMPORTANT
ABOUT HAVING THE OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION AND THE RENEWAL IS
THAT IT IS GOVERNED BY THE PUBLIC LAWS.
THE BROWN ACT WHICH GUARANTEES THE EFFECT THAT THE PUBLIC HAS
THE RIGHT TO ADDRESS THE THE BOARD AND TO BE ABLE TO SPEAK
AS TO HOW THE MONEY IS GOING TO BE SPENT.
AND SO IT GUARANTEES THAT PUBLIC INVOLVEMENT WHICH IS SO
VERY IMPORTANT. SO AGAIN I SPEAKING AS SOMEBODY
WHO WAS ON THE STEERING COMMITTEE THE GRANTED FROM FOR
THE FORMATION OF THE CBD BACK IN EARLY 2000S BUT ALSO WITH AN
INTERESTED MEMBER OF THE COMMUNITY THAT IS ACTIVE BUT
ALSO TO URGE YOU TO ENTHUSIASTICALLY VOTE IN PRO
AND IN FAVOR OF THE RENEWAL. THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR YOUR.
>> THANK YOU MADAM PRESIDENT. CIVIL SERVICE COMMISSION
PRESIDENT THANK YOU FOR YOUR VOICE >> FOR IDENTIFICATION
PURPOSES ONLY. OF COURSE.
OF COURSE. >> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
HELLO, BOARD. I'M SPEAKING AGAIN ON BEHALF OF
SMALL BUSINESSES TO THE CITY AND SUPPORT OF THE OCEAN CBD.
I'VE SEEN THE WORK OF CHRIS MARTIN WHEN HE WORKED AT SOMA
CBD AND SUPPORTED A LOT OF SMALL BUSINESSES DURING THE
COVID PANDEMIC ESPECIALLY ON FOLSOM STREET AND THE WORK THAT
THEY DID TO KEEP THOSE CLEAN STREETS CLEAN THE
RESPONSIVENESS FROM SMALL BUSINESSES WHEN THERE WAS FECES
AND NEEDLES ON THE FLOOR AS WELL AS POWER WASHING STREETS
THAT HAD URINE IN THEM. WE CALLED THEM AS EARLY AS SIX
IN THE MORNING SOMETIMES AND THEY GOT OUT THERE ON
SUNDAY MORNINGS TO MAKE SURE THAT THE BUSINESSES THAT WERE
SHUTTERED WERE ABLE TO OPEN UP AND HAVE OUR BLOCK PARTIES
STREET CLOSURES AND SO FORTH. AND SO I JUST WANT TO SAY THAT
I STRONGLY SUPPORT THIS ITEM BEFORE TO REISSUE AND EXTEND
THE DISTRICTS CORRIDOR TO BE ABLE TO ALSO SUPPORT THE
LAKESHORE VILLAGE AS A PREEMPTIVE PREVIOUS ALUMNI OF
LOWELL ASSOCIATES OF LAW HIGH SCHOOL.
WE USED TO GO TO THAT SHOPPING CENTER A LOT WHICH WAS BACK
IN THE DAYS LUCKY I'M DATING MYSELF BUT AN ARBY'S OVER THERE
. SO I REALLY THINK THAT AS MUCH
THAT THE CITY AND THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS CAN DO TO SUPPORT
SMALL BUSINESSES ALONG THE CORRIDOR ESPECIALLY WITH MAKING
SURE THE AREAS ARE CLEAN SO THAT PEOPLE CAN CONDUCT
BUSINESS AND GET IN THEIR OFFICES IS GREAT.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
MY NAME IS SOLILOQUY CHANDLER AND I'M DEFINITELY IN SUPPORT
OF THIS ITEM UNFORTUNATELY I FEEL HE WAS ASKING TOO LITTLE.
YOU KNOW ALL OF THE MILLIONS AND MILLIONS OF DOLLARS THAT
HAVE BEEN SPENT IN THIS CITY IN REGARDS TO THINGS THAT HAVE
BEEN EVIL AND CORRUPTION. I THINK UNFORTUNATELY IF IT
WASN'T SUCH A LOW PRICE YOU PROBABLY WOULD HAVE BEEN
DENIED. WE HAVE SEEN THIS ALL OVER
AND IT'S TIME FOR US TO HOLD THE CITY ACCOUNTABLE IN REGARDS
TO WHEN IT COMES TO THE BLACK NATION.
THEY CANNOT EVEN ASK FULLY WHAT THEY NEED TO START THEIR
BUSINESSES. SO ONCE AGAIN I AM IN AGREEANCE
TO THIS ITEM. >> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> NEXT SPEAKER HI MY NAME IS
ARUN THEY STERLING. I AM A RESIDENT OF D11, ALSO A
COMMUNITY ACTIVIST AND TEEN AS WELL TOO.
I HAVE A SMALL BUSINESS STERLING BUILDERS DOING
BUSINESS IN STERLING FRAMERS. I'M IN SUPPORT OF THE OCEAN
AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFITS. I'VE BEEN OVER THERE MY WHOLE
LIFE BUT ONE THING I DO WANT TO SAY ON RECORD IS THAT MAKE SURE
THAT WE ARE THAT YOU GUYS ARE REACHING OUT TO THE COMMUNITY,
TO SMALL BUSINESSES AS WELL TO DO THOSE PROJECTS OR WHATEVER
PROJECTS THAT YOU GUYS HAVE OVER THERE AND ALSO TO REACH
OUT TO THE COMMUNITY FOR COMMUNITY EMPLOYMENT AS WELL
TOO. SO THAT'S THANK YOU FOR YOUR
TIME. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
ALL RIGHT. LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER. >> WELCOME.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON TO EVERYONE. I'M A CALMING BASS THAT I AM A
PROPERTY OWNER IN OCEAN AVENUE. I'M JUST WONDERING BECAUSE A
THIS YEAR MY ASSESSMENT WAS 1895 IN I'M JUST WONDERING HOW
COME THAT BIG IT'S MORE THAN ONE THIRD OF MY PROPERTY TAX
AND IT MAYBE THE PRESENTATION IS REALLY GOOD BUT IF YOU WENT
TO A FROM THAT 13 HUNDRED DOWN THE TREES UP DYING NOBODY'S
MAINTAINING IT IN I WANT TO KNOW THE SERVICES PROVIDED
ACCOMPLISHMENT MADE AND WHAT WAS IT MAINTAIN IN MY AREA YOU
CAN SEE ALL THE TREES DYING AND NOBODY EVEN THE STRIP THEY
SAID THAT THEY THEY BOTHER WAS THE SIDEWALK THAT WHEN IT'S
THAT IT'S NOT BEEN OUR STREET THAT'S SO THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMMENTS I'M GOING TO ASK JACKIE HAZELWOOD JUST TO MEET
WITH THE RESIDENT AND ANSWER SOME OF HER QUESTIONS FOR HER.
THANK YOU. LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER. >> HI, MY NAME IS DENISE BURNS
AND I'M A RESIDENT OF LAKESIDE VILLAGE AND I'M ONE OF THE
CO-FOUNDERS OF THE LAKESIDE VILLAGE NONPROFIT IT I'M HERE
TO SPEAK IN SUPPORT OF JOINING THE OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION
AND SINCE 2020 VOLUNTEERS LIKE ME HAVE BEEN DOING HEAVY
LIFTING TO IMPROVE THE COMMERCIAL CORRIDOR ON ASIAN
OCEAN AVENUE AND LAKESIDE VILLAGE.
ONE OF OUR TOP PRIORITIES WAS AND STILL IS TO SUPPORT THE
SMALL LOCAL BUSINESSES WE ORGANIZED FREQUENT LITTER
PICKUPS. WE FUNDRAISED TO HAVE MURALS
PAINTED, TO HAVE MARKET LIGHTS INSTALLED ON THE SIDEWALKS
AND TO BEAUTIFY AND ADD PLANTS IN EVERY BIT OF EMPTY DIRT THAT
WAS AVAILABLE. WE JUST WANTED LOTS OF GREENERY
SO ALL THIS HARD WORK WAS DONE TO IMPROVE THE APPEAL AND THE
SAFETY OF THE AREA FOR BUSINESSES AND FOR THEIR
CUSTOMERS. >> IN 2023 WE STARTED TO WORK
WITH THE AA AND WOW WHAT A DIFFERENCE LIKE EVERYONE HAS
SAID THE POWER MACHINE THEY PULLED WEEDS, THEY PICKED UP
LITTER AND THEY EVEN HELPED WHEN SOME OF THE VACANT
STOREFRONTS HAD THEIR WINDOWS SMASHED OR THEIR DOORS MATCH SO
POSITIVE FEEDBACK ACROSS THE BOARD.
SADLY WE HAD TO CANCEL THAT RELATIONSHIP THE SERVICES WITH
THE WAY BECAUSE OF THE ASSET PARK ALLIANCE AND THE FACT THAT
THEY'VE BEEN SHUT DOWN. >> SO AS A RESULT THE CORRIDOR
IS BEGINNING TO LOOK MESSY AGAIN TRASH CANS OVERFILLED
THINGS LEFT ON THE SIDEWALK. YOU KNOW WE MISS ROLL AND WE
MISS THE YOU KNOW WE MISS THE TEAM.
>> IT IS IMPOSSIBLE FOR VOLUNTEERS LIKE US TO RAISE THE
FUNDS TO MAINTAIN THE COMMERCIAL CORRIDOR IN A
VIBRANT AND CLEAN FASHION. THE BEST PATH FORWARD IS FOR
LAKESIDE VILLAGE TO BECOME A PART OF.
OKAY. SO I ASK AND I HOPE THAT THE
PROPERTY OWNERS WILL VOTE IN FAVOR OF IT AND THAT YOU ALL
WILL VOTE TO EXTEND IT EXPANDED AND RENEW IT.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
WELCOME. >> HELLO SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS DEBRA MITCHELL AND I GUESS I REPRESENT THE MUCH
BELEAGUERED PROPERTY OWNERS OF OCEAN AVENUE AND I WANTED TO
EXPLAIN WHY I AM VERY MUCH IN FAVOR OF JOINING THE
ASSOCIATION AND IT'S CERTAINLY NOT NEWS THAT THE FAILURES OF
OUR SOCIETY ARE ON THE STREETS AROUND US ALL AND WE NEED MORE
HELP DIRECTLY ON THE STREETS AND THIS IS WHAT IT'S PROVIDING
AS A PROPERTY OWNER I HAVE CLEANED UP FECES.
I'VE HAD TO WAKE UNHOUSED PEOPLE IN THE MORNING.
I MEAN I TRY NOT TO WAKE THEM ACTUALLY I TRY TO WAIT TILL
THEY WAKE UP BUT STILL HAVING PEOPLE THERE FIRST THING IN THE
MORNING IS A HUGE HELP. IT'S MORE THAN ANY OF US CAN DO
INDIVIDUALLY AND WE JUST NEED TO PAY FOR THIS TO GET IT DONE.
IT'S OUR STREETS, IT'S OUR HOMES, IT'S OUR BUSINESSES.
>> IT'S OUR CITY. THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
>> I THANK YOU. MY NAME IS RANDY SWINDELL
AND I'M HERE TO SUPPORT THE OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION
AND THE EXTENSION TO LAKESIDE VILLAGE.
I'M A BOARD MEMBER OF UNITY SPIRITUAL CENTER.
WE ARE THE PROPERTY OWNER AT THE CORNER OF 19TH AVENUE
AND OCEAN WHERE THAT CUTE LITTLE TURQUOISE CHURCH AND THE
OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION PROVIDES IMPORTANT SERVICES TO
HELP CLEAN UP LITTER GRIME AND WORSE FROM OUR SIDEWALKS,
DOORWAYS AND GARDENS WE NEED OWNER'S HELP TO MAINTAIN
AND WEED THE SIDEWALKS, GARDENS REPLACE PLANTS WHEN THEY DIE.
WE'VE GOT A DYING TREE NEXT TO OUR PROPERTY AND WE JUST DON'T
HAVE ENOUGH VOLUNTEERS TO BE ABLE TO DO THAT KIND OF WORK
OURSELVES. >> AND WE DO HAVE AN ACTIVE
VOLUNTEER COMMUNITY BUT IT'S JUST IT'S NOT ADEQUATE.
WE REALLY APPRECIATE THE MARKETING AND PROMOTION THAT IS
DONE THROUGH NEWSLETTERS, SOCIAL MEDIA EVENTS AND OTHER
ACTIVITIES IN LAKESIDE VILLAGE. WE WANT TO BE PART OF OSHA
BECAUSE THIS WILL BENEFIT OUR CHURCH AND OUR ENTIRE COMMUNITY
AND I HAVE TO SAY I'VE BEEN THERE ABOUT FOUR YEARS AND WHEN
I GOT THERE IT WAS A WINDSWEPT GRAY JUST BLEAK LANDSCAPE
AND NOW IT IS VIBRANT AND COLORFUL AND CLEAN AND JUST
AN EXCITING PLACE TO BE. SO LET'S VOTE YES AND THANK YOU
SO MUCH FOR YOUR TIME. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER .
>> THANK YOU. MY NAME IS KAT CYCLE I GUESS I
HOPE I'M PRONOUNCING THAT CORRECTLY.
>> I'M HERE TO SPEAK IN SUPPORT OF THE OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION
AFTER WE STARTED THE BUSINESS COUNCIL IN 2021 WE DID A SURVEY
OF THE SMALL BUSINESSES AND THE NUMBER ONE PRIORITIES WERE
CLEAN, SAFE, BRIGHTLY LIT STREETS WITH HIGHER FOOTFALL OF
CUSTOMERS AND FEWER EMPTY BUILDINGS.
SO NO SURPRISES THERE. WHILE IT WAS QUITE EASY, DENISE
SPOKE TO THE WORK WE DID TO APPLY FOR GRANTS AS VOLUNTEERS
IT WAS QUITE EASY TO FIND GRANTS FOR NEW SHINY OBJECTS
LIKE MURALS OR A STAGE IN THE LITTLE COMMUNITY PARK WE CALLED
LAKESIDE LANDING. >> IT WAS REALLY HARD TO RAISE
THE MONEY FOR BASIC CLEANING SERVICES.
IN FACT IT TOOK US TWO YEARS SO REALLY HAPPY TO HEAR THE PEOPLE
THAT HAVE NOTICED THE DIFFERENCE.
JULY 2023 OKAY STARTED AND SINCE THE PARKS ALLIANCE
IMPLOSION WE REALLY MISS THEM SO I WANTED ALSO TO MENTION
THAT OKAY WITH A BEST VALUE WHEN WE GOT OUR GRANT WE WE
WENT OUT AND GOT QUOTES AND THEY WERE TWICE THE QUALITY
TWICE THE FREQUENCY FOR HALF THE PRICE.
SO I REALLY FEEL LIKE THIS IS A GOOD VALUE FOR THE PROPERTY
OWNERS AND I WANT TO READ A COUPLE OF QUOTES FROM PEOPLE
WHO COULDN'T BE HERE WHO ARE PROPERTY AND BUSINESS OWNERS.
ONE OF OUR PROPERTY OWNERS SAID WE WANT TO BE PART OF THE OKAY
BECAUSE THIS WILL BENEFIT OUR BUSINESS AS WELL AS THE ENTIRE
COMMERCIAL CORRIDOR AND MANY OTHERS.
I WON'T READ THEM ALL HIGHLIGHTED HERE.
>> SO VOLUNTEERS AS DENISE SAID ,WE STILL ORGANIZE MONTHLY
CLEANUPS BECAUSE THE KIDS LOVE TO DO THEIR COMMUNITY SERVICE
BUT WE CAN'T POSSIBLY KEEP ON TOP OF A BUSY COMMERCIAL
CORRIDOR. SO WE URGE YOU TO VOTE YES FOR
CLEAN, SAFE, VIBRANT STREET AND WE HOPE THAT THE EXPANSION
WILL BE APPROVED. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER
. >> GOOD AFTERNOON BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS HOWARD CHUNG.
>> I'M A LIFELONG SAN FRANCISCO RESIDENT AND A COMMERCIAL
PROPERTY OWNER. I OWNED THE PROPERTY AT FAXON
AND OCEAN AVENUE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> I'VE ALSO BEEN A MEMBER OF THE BOARD OF DIRECTORS OF THE
OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION SINCE ITS INCEPTION.
>> SO AS A PROPERTY OWNER AND INVESTOR I LOOK VERY SIMPLY
AT THE AMOUNT OF THE ASSESSMENT VERSUS THE VALUE ADD THAT THE
OWNER BRINGS. AND I CAN SAY WHOLEHEARTEDLY
THAT I'VE ALWAYS SUPPORTED AND SUPPORT THE EXPANSION
AND RENEWAL OF THE OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION THE WAY CLEAN
SIDEWALKS PICKS UP TRASH IN SHORT THE QUARTERS IS JUST A
LOT CLEANER. SECONDLY, THERE'S A CONSTANT
SAFETY AND COMMUNITY PRESENCE WITH THE WAY THAT TRANSLATES TO
WHAT I BELIEVE TO BE LESS CRIME AND PARTNERSHIP WITH SAPD
AND THE PERCEPTION OF LESS CRIME.
>> THE AIR IS ALSO A DRIVER OF ECONOMIC VITALITY AND BUSINESS
SUPPORT. THEY'VE SUPPORTED A NUMBER OF
GREAT EVENTS INCLUDING THE ART POP UP SERIES WINE TASTING AT
VARIOUS OCEAN AVENUE BUSINESSES AND LIVE MUSIC EVENTS.
AND ALSO THE SUPPORTS AND HOLDS BUSINESS ASSISTANCE PROGRAMS
AND ESPECIALLY ADVOCATES FOR CHINESE-AMERICAN OWNED
BUSINESSES IN THE AREA. >> I THINK THE AA IS THE I
THINK THE SMALLEST CBD BUT YET IT REALLY PUNCHES ABOVE ITS
WEIGHT IN TERMS OF GETTING GRANTS, GIVING BUSINESS
ASSISTANCE AND SHAPING PUBLIC POLICY FOR THE AREA.
>> SO I INVITE EACH OF THE MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS TO COME TO OCEAN AVENUE AND CHECK OUT THE
BUSINESSES THAT WE HAVE THERE. >> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER
. GOOD AFTERNOON.
GOOD AFTERNOON TO THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS HENRY COBAIN. I AM A RESIDENT OF WESTWOOD
PARK WHICH IS ADJACENT TO THE OCEAN AVENUE CORRIDOR.
I HAVE BEEN A MEMBER OF THE BOARD OF DIRECTORS OF THE OCEAN
AVENUE ASSOCIATION SINCE IT WAS FOUNDED IN 2010 AND I'M NOT
HERE TO REPEAT ALL THE THINGS YOU'VE HEARD ABOUT THE SERVICES
THAT THE CBD PROVIDES. USING THE ASSESSMENT DOLLARS I
WANT INSTEAD CALL YOUR ATTENTION TO ANOTHER ASPECT OF
THIS WONDERFUL ORGANIZATION AND THAT IS THE OCEAN AVENUE
ASSOCIATION ITSELF WHICH IS ALL VOLUNTEER NEIGHBORHOOD BASED,
COMMUNITY DRIVEN. AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR, YOU
EARLIER HAD THANKED SUPERVISE FOR APPLAUSE FOR ALL THE WORK
HE DID TO FOUND THIS CBD. >> HE DID IT WITH THE
INSPIRATION AND THE HELP OF OUR LEGENDARY COMMUNITY ACTIVIST
DAN WEAVER. AND I JUST WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE
AND RECOGNIZE THE SPIRIT OF DAN WEAVER AND ALL THAT HE STOOD
FOR IN MAKING THIS ORGANIZATION POSSIBLE.
LIVES ON. WE STILL ARE A VOICE OF THE
NEIGHBORHOOD. WE STILL HOPE TO WORK WITH THE
CITY TO IMPROVE THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
WE'RE HERE TO LISTEN. WE'RE HERE TO CONVEY
NEIGHBORHOOD FEELINGS BACK TO THE CITY.
AND THAT IS AS IMPORTANT AS THE USE OF THE ASSESSMENT DOLLARS
TO CLEAN, BEAUTIFY AND IMPROVE THE SAFETY OF THE CORRIDOR.
SO THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR YOUR ATTENTION.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS AND WE WILL WELCOME THE NEXT
SPEAKER. ARE THERE ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF
THE PUBLIC WHO WOULD LIKE TO ADDRESS THE BOARD DURING THE
OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT PUBLIC HEARING?
ALL RIGHT. THIS WILL BE OUR LAST SPEAKER.
WELCOME. >> HI EVERYONE.
MY NAME'S TIFFANY SINGH AND I AM A PROPERTY OWNER BUSINESS
OWNER AND A BOARD DIRECTOR OF OCA.
AND I'M HERE TO STRONG TO URGE EVERYONE AND MY SEND MY STRONG
SUPPORT TO RENEWING THE OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION.
OVER THE YEARS I HAVE BEEN PLAYING A KEY ROLE IN KEEPING
OUR CORRIDOR SAFE, VIBRANT AND THRIVING.
AND THIS RENEWAL ISN'T JUST IMPORTANT.
IT'S NECESSARY FOR CONTINUED WELL-BEING FOR OUR
NEIGHBORHOOD. AND WITH THE RENEWAL AA CAN AA
CAN CONTINUE TO SUPPORT PUBLIC SAFETY THROUGH OUR PARTNERSHIP
WITH THE CITY'S AND ALSO WITH THE NEW OWNER.
IT WILL HELP SMALL BUSINESS MICE SURVIVE AND GROW WITH
RESOURCE TECHNICAL SUPPORT AND FUNDING SUPPORT AS WELL.
>> AND MOST IMPORTANTLY SERVING AS A STRONG UNIT AT WEISS OF
OCEAN AVENUE. WHEN WE SPEAK TO THE CITY
AND ADVOCATES FOR OUR COMMUNITY IT'S A WOUND IN A WAY IT'S MORE
THAN JUST A ORGANIZATION. IT IS A FORCE FOR CONNECTION
ADVOCACY AND PROGRESS. I HOPE EVERYONE WITH STAND WITH
US IN SUPPORTING THIS RENEWAL AND WE CAN KEEP THE BUILDING
BETTER AND SAFE THAT BETTER SAFETY FOR OCEAN AVENUE AND FOR
THE NEIGHBORS. >> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. ALL RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> ALL RIGHT. SEEING NO OTHER SPEAKERS PUBLIC
COMMENT YEAH, I'D LIKE TO SPEAK FOR THE BOARD OF THAT HAD ALL
THESE ENORMOUS FIGURES. THOSE FIGURES ARE NOT THE TRUTH
. THE TRUTH IS THAT THAT
COMMERCIAL DISTRICT OF OCEAN AVENUE HAS FROM FRIDA KAHLO
STREET TO EL REY 15 VACANT BUSINESS IS THAT HAVE AND TWO
OF THEM ONE IS A $50,000 15,000 SQUARE FOOT BUSINESS.
THE OTHER ONE IS AT LEAST 10,000 AND THERE WALGREENS HAS
LEFT. BUSINESSES ARE LEAVING
AND THEY'RE LEAVING BECAUSE NOT JUST THE ASSESSMENT THE
ASSESSMENT IS SOMETHING PILED ON TO EXCESSIVE TAXES, BUSINESS
TAX, PROPERTY TAXES. YOU HAVE TO BE REALISTIC.
YOU CAN'T DO BUSINESS IN A CITY THAT CONSTANTLY DRAINS THE
ECONOMY VITALITY THROUGH WHAT THEY CALL NONPROFITS.
THESE ARE NOT NONPROFITS. >> THEORY ARE CREATED TO CREATE
JOBS FOR HIGHLY EDUCATED, VERY CLEVER PEOPLE AND SEND OUT A
FEW PEOPLE TO CLEAN THE STREETS, PACK BAG THE BAGS
OUTSIDE AND THEN THEN PUBLIC WORKS COMES ALONG WITH THEIR
ARMY OF EMPLOYEES AND PICKS UP ALL THE GARBAGE.
THIS IS A BOONDOGGLE AND IF YOU WANT TO HELP LOWER THE TAXES,
RESTRICT THE ASSESSMENTS, STRIP PAINT AND RESTRICT THE YEARS
THAT THEY WANT AND THE IDEA THAT LAKESIDE VILLAGE IS GOING
TO BECOME PART OF THIS IS AN ABSOLUTE ABSURDITY A LAKESIDE
VILLAGE IS DIVIDED BY DUE TO PACIRA A VERY LARGE, VERY LARGE
DIFFICULT STREET TO GET ACROSS. >> THERE ARE TWO SEPARATE
ENTITIES THANK YOU VERY MUCH. I MEAN I COULD GO ON BUT I HEAR
THAT BUZZER THAT MUST MEAN MY TIME IS UP RIGHT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH. PLEASE THINK ABOUT WHAT I SAID
. >> YOU HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY TO
REALLY HELP BY LOWERING TAXES LOWING ASSESSMENT AND LOWERING
THE YEARS THAT THIS NONPROFIT IS BEEN.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. MR. DUFFY ARE YOU HERE TO SPEAK
ON THE OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT?
OKAY. WELCOME.
I JUST CAN'T SEE IT ENDING ON THAT NOTE FROM THE COMMENT I
LIVE IN A NEIGHBORHOOD IN A FEW BLOCKS AWAY FROM HERE AND I
THINK IT'S JUST WONDERFUL PEOPLE ARE TRYING TO KEEP UP
THE QUALITY OF LIFE IN THEIR NEIGHBORHOODS AND I THINK IT'S
KIND OF ODD THAT THE FUNDING FOR THE QUALITY OF LIFE IN MY
NEIGHBORHOOD IS UNDER ATTACK RIGHT NOW.
THE OTHER THING I WOULD SAY IS THAT IF WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
SUCH LARGE ADULT PEOPLE TALKING HERE, MAYBE THERE COULD BE AN
EXTENSION FOR THE FOR THE MICROPHONE FOR THE LARGER
PEOPLE. >> THANK YOU.
MR. DUFFY ARE THERE ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC WHO WOULD
LIKE TO ADDRESS THE BOARD ON THE OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY
BENEFIT DISTRICT? >> PLEASE COME FORWARD, SIR.
YEAH. CAN I HAVE THE CHANCE?
PLEASE PROCEED. GOOD LEADERS, EVERYONE.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON. THIS IS FOR THE OCEAN AVENUE
COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT. >> WELCOME.
I CANNOT SPEAK VERY WELL. I'M SO OKAY WE'LL LISTEN.
I'M SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO MINUTES.
I JUST WANT TO KNOW WHO'S ASSIGNED TO CLEAN THE STREET
PUBLIC WORKS OR THE ASSOCIATION OF OCEAN BECAUSE I WOULD I
WOULD NEED TO GO WORK. >> I ASSUME THAT TO CLEAN UP
ALSO AROUND THE THREE CAN YOU USE THE MICROPHONES OR SPEAK
INTO THE MICROPHONE SO EVERYWHERE YOU JUST SPEAK UP
MACDONALD THING AND UNDER THE TREES LEAVES IT'S ACCUMULATED
ON THE STREET OCEAN AND THEN ANOTHER CIRCUIT TO USE THE
MICROPHONE SPEAK INTO THE MICROPHONE PLEASE.
THANK YOU. I LOST AND I'M THE ONE SWEEPING
AROUND MY BUILDING. >> I THINK THEY SHOULD KEEPING
THAT THEY'RE DOING A GOOD JOB. >> SOME OTHERS ARE DOING A GOOD
JOB BUT I TALK TO THAT GUY AND ANOTHER GUY THEY SHOULD
THIS PUBLIC WORKS WHAT UNIFORM HAVE I SAID NO.
NO SIGN OF WHAT PUBLIC WORKS OR ASSOCIATION UNIFORM YELLOW.
YES, I SAID YELLOW AND OH DOESN'T NOT NATIONAL PUBLIC
WORKS JUMP AND THEN I TALKED TO THE SAME GUY AGAIN ONE TIME
AND HE SAID HE WORKS FOR THE UNION UNION GUY.
>> SO IT DEPENDS. I THINK WE ASSIGNED OR CLEANED
THE STREET SO THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
I DON'T HAVE TO LISTEN OUTDOOR GUY IN LOS YES MAYBE BUT I
JUST WANT TO SAY SOMETHING ABOUT BECAUSE I'M CLEANING MY
OWN AREA AND I COULD GO TIMES ALREADY BUT JUST TRIPPIN.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS OR JACKIE HAZELWOOD ARE YOU STILL
IN THE CHAMBER? >> CAN YOU ANSWER HIS QUESTION
PLEASE? THANK YOU MUCH.
>> THANK YOU SIR. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
THANK YOU SIR. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS SIR.
YOU'RE DONE. YOUR COMMENT IS OVER.
>> THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT. ANY OTHER SPEAKERS TO ADDRESS
THE BOARD ON THE OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT?
>> ALL RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT. >> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. SEEING NO OTHER SPEAKERS,
PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED. >> SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU,
PRESIDENT GENTLEMEN, I AM JUST A BIG BELIEVER IN COMMUNITY
BENEFIT DISTRICTS AND I'M BLESSED TO REPRESENT A DISTRICT
THAT HAS SOME EXCELLENT CBDS. SO THIS IS GOING TO BE AN EASY
CALL FOR ME BUT I DIDN'T WANT TO LET THE MOMENT PASS TO ADD
THAT I'M ALSO A BIG BELIEVER IN CHRISTIAN MARTIN WITH WHOM
I'VE HAD THE CHANCE TO WORK AS A MID-MARKET RESIDENT BEFORE I
JOINED THE BOARD BACK WHEN HE WAS RUNNING THE SOMA WEST CBD.
SO THE OCEAN AVENUE ASSOCIATION HAS AN EXTRAORDINARILY
CONSCIENTIOUS AND ACCOMPLISHED LEADER AND CHRISTIAN, YOU'RE
LUCKY TO HAVE HIM. I WANT TO EXPRESS MY THANKS TO
SUPERVISOR MELGAR AND CHEN FOR THEIR HARD WORK AND LEADERSHIP
ON THIS AND I'M HAPPY TO SUPPORT IT.
>> RIGHT. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR DORSEY
SEEING NO OTHER NAMES ON THE ROSTER.
THE HEARING HAS BEEN HELD AND IS NOW FILED NOW I BELIEVE
THAT SUPERVISOR CHEN WAS GOING TO MAKE AN PROPOSE AN AMENDMENT
. >> OKAY.
THANK YOU PRESIDENT MENDHAM AND AGAIN I AM INTRODUCING
AMENDMENTS TO THE RESOLUTION TO ESTABLISH THE OCEAN AVENUE
COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT. >> THE PROPOSED AMENDMENTS
UPDATE THE MANAGEMENT PLAN AND ENGINEERS REPORT AS OF JULY
2025 EXTRA COPIES OF THIS AMENDED PLANS ARE AVAILABLE
TODAY FOR THE PUBLIC TO REVIEW AND PUBLIC COMMENTS SO IT'S
WELCOME DURING THE TESTIMONY PORTION OF TODAY'S HEARING THE
PROPOSED AMENDMENTS INCLUDING A REDUCTION TO THE ORIGINAL
PROPOSED BOUNDARIES AS OF APRIL 2025 IT WILL REMOVE 54
NONCOMMERCIAL PARCELS LOCATED ALONG THE SOUTHERN AND NORTHERN
SIDE OF GENEVA AVENUE BETWEEN OCEAN BETWEEN OCEAN AVENUE
AND THE I TO 80 OFF RAMP. THE TOTAL NUMBER OF PARCELS
IN THE PROPOSED DISTRICT WILL BE REDUCED FROM 339 TO 285
PARCELS. THIS 54 PARCELS REPRESENT
44,000 $491.27 IN ASSESSMENT REVENUES WITH THIS REDUCTION
DEMAND AN ASSESSMENT TOTAL WILL BE $435,088.36 THE PARCELS
BEING REMOVED IT ARE NONCOMMERCIAL IN USE AND ARE
LOCATED AT THE EDGE OF THE DISTRICT.
THEIR REMOVAL WILL NOT AFFECT THE SERVICES DELIVERED TO THE
REST OF THE DISTRICT. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR SHANNON SO THERE'S A
MOTION AND IT HAS BEEN SECONDED BY SUPERVISOR MELGAR AND I
BELIEVE WE CAN TAKE THOSE AMENDMENTS WITHOUT OBJECTION.
>> SO WITHOUT OBJECTION THE AMENDMENTS ARE APPROVED.
>> THE BALLOTS WILL NOW BE TABULATED AND WE WILL RETURN TO
ITEM 40 AFTER THE DEPARTMENT OF ELECTIONS REPORTS THE RESULTS
MEMBERS MAY PROVIDE ADDITIONAL COMMENT AT THAT TIME BEFORE WE
CONSIDER THE RESOLUTION TO ESTABLISH AND MADAM CLERK WITH
THAT I THINK WE GO BACK TO PUBLIC TO GENERAL PUBLIC
COMMENT. >> ALL RIGHT.
THE PUBLIC WHO ARE HERE FOR GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT PLEASE
LINE UP ON YOUR RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER.
I WILL JUST CAUTION YOU DO NOT SPEAK ABOUT PROPOSITION C,
DON'T TALK ABOUT THE BUDGET ITEMS WHICH HAVE BEEN CONTINUED
TO JUNE 5TH JULY 15TH BUT YOU MAY SPEAK ABOUT YOUR
EXPERIENCE. >> WELCOME.
WE'RE SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO MINUTES.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON. I'M ALISHA ROCHELLE.
I AM AN AMERICAN. AMERICANS ARE CITIZENS OF THE
UNITED STATES OF AMERICA. >> FEDERAL LAW DOES NOT EQUATE
NATIONALITY WITH RACE OR ETHNICITY BUT RATHER WITH
CITIZENSHIP. THE MAJORITY OF AMERICANS OR
THEIR ANCESTORS IMMIGRATED TO THE UNITED STATES OR ARE
DESCENDANTS FROM PEOPLE WHO ARE BROUGHT AS SLAVES WITHIN THE
PAST FIVE CENTURIES. WITH THE EXCEPTION OF THE
NATIVE AMERICAN POPULATION. SO THE ADJECTIVE DISENFRANCHIZE
DESCRIBES A PERSON OR GROUP OF PEOPLE WHO ARE STRIPPED OF
THEIR POWER LIKE DISENFRANCHIZE POST-CIVIL WAR AFRICAN
AMERICANS WHO WERE DEPRIVED OF THEIR RIGHT TO VOTE EVEN AFTER
BEING FREED FROM SAY SLAVERY. BEING DISENFRANCHIZED IS NO
FUN. THE RULES WORK AGAINST YOU.
YOUR RIGHTS ARE CONSTANTLY VIOLATED AND YOU HAVE LITTLE
POWER TO CHANGE YOUR LIFE FOR THE BETTER.
THE OLD FRENCH WORD IN FRENCH HERE MEANS TO MAKE FREE.
AND WHEN YOU ADD THE NEGATIVE PREFIX DIS DISENFRANCHIZE MEANS
MADE UNFREE A DISENFRANCHIZE POPULATION DOESN'T REST EASY
AND OFTEN THEY ORGANIZE AND FIGHT BACK AGAINST THEIR
CONDITION TO DEMAND THEIR BASIC RIGHTS AND FREEDOM.
THAT'S HOW WE WANT OUR BASIC RIGHTS AND FREEDOM.
WE ARE ALSO SAN FRANCISCANS LOVE ON YOUR SAN FRANCISCANS.
I'M NOT FEELING THE LOVE AS A BLACK WOMAN, AS AN
AFRICAN-AMERICAN WOMAN, AS AN AMERICAN.
THIS IS WHERE I'M CHOOSING TO LIVE.
MAKE ME FEEL COMFORTABLE HERE. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS, SIR.
>> I DID YOU ALREADY PROVIDE GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT?
>> NO, NOT ON THIS. NO.
OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
>> WELL, WELCOME. THANK YOU.
APPRECIATE YOU GETTING GOOD AFTERNOON.
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS CHAIR. MY NAME AGAIN.
MY NAME IS LAUREN DE STERLING AND I'M A PROUD MEMBER OF SAN
FRANCISCO'S BLACK BUSINESS COMMUNITY AND SAN FRANCISCO
BLACK COMMUNITY. I'M HERE TO URGE THIS BOARD TO
CONTINUE INVESTING IN BLACK COMMUNITIES BECAUSE THE NEED IS
URGING AND THE IMPACT IS REAL. FOR DECADES BLACK NEIGHBORHOODS
HAVE BEEN SYSTEMATICALLY AND UNDERFUNDED WHILE OUR
BUSINESSES FIGHT FOR SURVIVAL WITH LIMITED ACCESS TO CAPITAL
CONTRACTS AND OPPORTUNITIES. WE'RE NOT ASKING FOR FAVORS.
WE'RE ASKING FOR FAIR INVESTMENT IN COMMUNITIES THAT
HAVE GIVEN SO MUCH TO THIS CITY.
WHEN WE FUND BLACK OWNED BUSINESSES, WE'RE NOT JUST
SUPPORTING ENTREPRENEURS. WE'RE CREATING JOBS, PRESERVING
CULTURE, STABILIZING FAMILIES AND BUILDING LONG TERM WEALTH
IN THE NEIGHBORHOODS THAT NEED IT.
THAT NEED IN MOST EQUITY IS NOT ACHIEVED WITH STATEMENTS IT'S
ACHIEVED WITH BUDGETS. AND I WANT TO CLOSE WITH THIS.
WE DO NOT WANT TO ROLL BACK THE HARD WON GAINS THAT WERE MADE.
THOSE INVESTMENTS SAVED LIVES, CREATED JOBS AND BROUGHT
DIGNITY TO COMMUNITIES THAT HAD LONG BEEN DENIED IT.
TO ABANDON THEM NOW IS TO WALK AWAY FROM THE COMMITMENTS MADE
DURING THE CITY'S SO-CALLED RACIAL RECKONING.
BUDGETS ARE MORAL DOCUMENTS. THEY REVEAL WHAT AND WHO WE
TRULY VALUE. WE URGE THIS BOARD TO PROVE
THAT YOUR PROMISES WERE MORE THAN SYMBOLIC.
UPLIFT THE BLACK COMMUNITY, DELIVER ON EQUITY AND DO WHAT'S
RIGHT. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. SOLILOQUY A CHANDLER ONCE AGAIN
AND I'M REALLY KIND OF CONFUSED CONCERNING THE PROPOSITION 209
THAT STATES THAT NO COMMUNITY CAN RECEIVE FUNDING IN THE NAME
OF OUR RACE. >> IT'S INTERESTING TO ME THAT
THE SANCTUARY CITY WAS ABLE TO RECEIVE MILLIONS AND MILLIONS
OF DOLLARS. THE ASIAN COMMUNITY WAS ABLE TO
RECEIVE MONEY IN THE NAME OF ASIAN HATE.
I'M REALLY CONFUSED HERE THE APA WHICH IS THE ASIAN PACIFIC.
THEY HAVE THE ASIAN FAMILY SUPPORT SERVICE, ASIAN HERITAGE
FOUNDATION, ASIAN CULTURAL CENTER, ASIAN LEGAL OUTREACH,
ASIAN INC ASIAN LOCAL CAUCUS ASIAN PACIFIC AMERICAN AMERICAN
COMMUNITY CENTER BE CHINATOWN BRIGHT LINE DEFENSE PROJECT
CENTER FOR ASIAN AMERICAN MEDIA CHARITY CULTURAL SERVICES
CHINATOWN ASIAN COMMUNITY CHILDREN'S CENTER CHINATOWN
COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT CHINATOWN TOWN M.K. YMCA CHINESE CULTURAL
CENTER OF SAN FRANCISCO. CHINESE FOR AFFIRMATIVE ACTION
CHINESE HISTORICAL SOCIETY OF AMERICA CHINESE NEWCOMERS
SERVICE CENTER CHINESE PROGRESSIVES ASSOCIATION
CHINATOWN MILLION ARTS COLLABORATIVE COALITION FOR
COMMUNITY SAFETY AND JUSTICE ON AND ON AND ON AND ON.
>> WHAT'S GOING ON AROUND HERE? WHAT IS THE DECEPTION GOING ON
AROUND HERE THAT YOU TAKE 60 MILLION THAT WAS SUPPOSED TO BE
FOR THE BLACK COMMUNITY AND GIVE IT TO EVERYBODY WHO'S
NOT WORKING WITH THE BLACK COMMUNITY WHO WE DON'T KNOW WHO
THEY ARE, THE EVIL AND THE WICKEDNESS THAT YOU'RE DOING A
VANEGAS MINE SAY OF YOUR WELL OR HIM AND YOU'RE GOING TO REAP
WHAT YOU SOW. I'M JUST HERE TO WARN EVERY ONE
OF YOU TO DECEITFULNESS THAT YOU HAVE BEEN PLANNED ALL THESE
YEARS IS NOW COMING BACK TO HAUNT YOU.
>> THE BLACK SAYING NEVER ASKS FOR MUCH MORE LATER.
>> DAISY TOO. THANK YOU SALAH THANK YOU FOR
YOUR COMMENTS. >> LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER. THANK YOU SALAH.
>> I THANK YOU SALAH. WELCOME, MR. KLEIN.
IT WILL COME AND COLLECT THAT FROM YOU.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON, BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
FOR THE RECORD MY NAME IS CHRISTOPHER KLEIN.
I ALSO GO BY SERGEANT KLEIN OF THE UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS
. SO I'M HANDING OUT A
SURVEILLANCE OVERVIEW FOR THE NEXT COUPLE OF WEEKS COUPLE OF
MONTHS. THIS IS GOING TO BE THE NUMBER
ONE TOPIC THAT EVERYONE IN THIS ROOM IS GOING TO BE DEALING
WITH. I'M KIND OF BROKE IT DOWN NAME
VARIATIONS, DIGITAL SURVEILLANCE, HEALTH
SURVEILLANCE, GANG SURVEILLANCE, PRISONS
SURVEILLANCE AND SO ON AND SO ON.
THE CDC ACCEPTABLE GUIDELINES FOR SURVEILLANCE IS BRIEF
AND NOT LONG LASTING AND NOT TO IMPEDE A PERSON'S FINANCIAL
EDUCATION AND OR INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY.
THERE'S ISSUES WITH SYNERGY STACKING OF SURVEILLANCE JUST
AN EXAMPLE OF STACKING IS I WAS BORN IN PENNSYLVANIA SO PENN
STATE THINKS THAT THEY OWN MY HEALTH CARE.
I GREW UP IN MARYLAND. AMERICAN UNIVERSITY UNIVERSITY
OF MARYLAND THINKS THEY OWN MY HEALTH CARE.
I MOVED TO SAN FRANCISCO, WORKED IN LA, UCSF, UCLA.
THEY THINK THEY OWN MY HEALTH CARE SO I HAVE LIKE 9 OR 10
COMPETING HEALTH CARES. AND THAT CREATES A STACKING.
SO WHEN SOMEBODY WANTS TO DO AN INTERVIEW OR A QUESTIONNAIRE AT
NIGHT THERE'S NO TIME. SO AT 1:00 THEY COME IN WITH
THEIR INTERVIEW. AND IT KEEPS PEOPLE UP SOME
PEOPLE TO GET OVER THAT THEY WANT TO GET UP AND HAVE A DRINK
OR MAYBE THEY DO DRUGS OR WHATEVER TO DEAL WITH THAT.
THAT CREATES OVERDOSES AND SUICIDES.
SO AGAIN, THIS IS JUST A HANDOUT BUT WE'RE RECOMMENDING
THAT THE DEPARTMENT HEADS CONVENE AN EMERGENCY MEETING TO
DETERMINE APPROPRIATE HIERARCHY OF SURVEILLANCE NEED IT
NECESSITY OF A PERSON'S HEALTH CARE OVER OTHER EXISTING ISSUES
,COURT ORDERS GOOD OF PUBLIC HEALTH SAFETY WITH RESPECT TO A
PERSON'S PRIVACY AND TO ELIMINATE EXCESSIVE NOISE FROM
THIRD PARTIES SUCH AS OTHER CITIES, COUNTIES, STATES,
UNIVERSITIES AND FOREIGN GOVERNMENTS BOTH FRIENDLY
AND ADVERSARY ADVERSARIES. AND MY CONTACT INFORMATION IS
THERE FOR ADDITIONAL INFORMATION IF YOU NEED
ASSISTANCE AND WE HAVE TO GET THROUGH THIS WE HAVE TO DO A
BETTER JOB OF ELIMINATING THE NOISE AND EXTERNAL SURVEILLANCE
FROM OTHER AREAS OTHER CITIES, UNIVERSITIES AND FOREIGN
COUNTRIES. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER GOOD AFTERNOON
SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS STEPHANIE PINKHAM.
I'M A FIFTH GENERATION SAN FRANCISCAN AND I HAVE RENTED MY
CURRENT HOME FOR THE PAST 20 YEARS.
I'M HERE TODAY TO ASK WHAT IS THE POINT OF A RESTRAINING
ORDER IF NO ONE WILL ENFORCE IT?
I HAVE BOTH A CIVIL HARASSMENT RESTRAINING ORDER AND A
CRIMINAL PROTECTIVE ORDER AGAINST MY NEIGHBOR PRESTON
MARX. HE VIOLATES SOME DAILY ENTERING
RESTRICTED AREAS THREATENING ME ,STALKING ME AND RELENTLESSLY
HARASSING ME AND MY DOGS. I REPORT THESE VIOLATIONS BUT
SFPD REFUSES TO ARREST THEM. I'VE BEEN TOLD RESTRAINING
ORDERS ARE JUST CIVIL MATTERS. THE OFFICERS HAVE MORE
IMPORTANT THINGS TO DO THAT THEY'RE SHORT STAFFED OR BUSY
AND THAT UNLESS THERE'S GRAVE BODILY INJURY THEY WON'T ARREST
. IT'S CLEAR MANY OFFICERS VIEW
THESE VIOLATIONS AS A DISTRACTION FROM REAL CRIMES
EVEN WORSE. MANY OFFICERS DON'T KNOW HOW TO
READ RESTRAINING ORDERS. I'VE HAD TO POINT OUT KEY TERMS
ONLY TO BE TOLD THE COURT ISSUED FORMS ARE UNCLEAR.
OFFICERS ALSO DON'T SEEM TO UNDERSTAND THE CONTROLLING
PRIORITY OF THE CPO. >> ON MULTIPLE OCCASIONS
OFFICERS HAVE TOLD ME TO GO BACK TO COURT AND GET A BETTER
ORDER. >> BUT WHEN I GO TO COURT I'M
TOLD THE POLICE ARE NOT DOING THEIR JOB.
THIS IS AN IMPOSSIBLE SITUATION AS A VICTIM.
OFFICERS SAY THEIR JOB IS TO DE-ESCALATE BUT THAT DOESN'T
PROTECT VICTIMS. ACCOUNTABILITY DOES.
THIS ISN'T JUST ABOUT ME. >> COURT RECORDS SHOW MULTIPLE
ADDITIONAL RESTRAINING ORDERS ALONG WITH PENDING CIVIL
AND CRIMINAL MATTERS REGARDING MR. WORKS.
THIS IS NOT A PRIVATE CONFLICT. IT'S A PUBLIC SAFETY FAILURE
PLAYING OUT IN REAL TIME IN A CITY THAT CLAIMS TO PROTECT
TENANTS AND VULNERABLE RESIDENTS.
AS THE CITY'S LEGISLATIVE LEADERSHIP YOU ARE ALL
RESPONSIBLE FOR PUBLIC SAFETY AND THIS IS WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE
WHEN THAT PROMISE BREAKS DOWN. A RESIDENT STANDING BEFORE YOU
BEGGING FOR ACTION, BEGGING FOR POLICE AND PROSECUTORS TO BE
GIVEN THE MANDATE, THE TRAINING, THE STAFFING AND THE
FINANCIAL RESOURCES TO ENFORCE COURT ORDERS SO THAT I
AND OTHERS LIKE ME DO NOT HAVE TO LIVE IN CONSTANT FEAR.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS .
>> I'M GOING TO TELL YOU SOMETHING QUITE REMARKABLE.
YOU SHOULD READ A BOOK CALLED THE LIGHT AND THE GLORY BY
PETER MARSHALL AND IT JUST TALKS ABOUT THE HAND OF GOD ON
OUR NATION AND IT'S IN DANIEL WE READ ABOUT 2300 YEARS AND IF
YOU START THE 2300 YEARS FROM THE BEGINNING OF THE TIMES
IN THE GENTILES REMEMBER I TOLD YOU WHEN TRUMP MADE HIS
PROCLAMATION IT WAS 360 SABBATICAL CYCLES AND 360
MONTHS FROM THE START OF THE TIMES OF THE GENTILES.
>> IT'S STRANGE BECAUSE IT WAS 2300 YEARS TO 1776 NOBODY
EVIDENTLY KNEW THAT BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T ADJUST THE
CHRONOLOGY TO THE YEAR THAT CHRIST WAS BAPTIZED.
IT'S A VERY SOLID YEAR IN LUKE CHAPTER THREE.
IT WAS THE 15TH OF TIBERIUS CAESAR.
>> IT WAS 28 A.D. ON THE GREGORIAN CALENDAR AND IT WAS
THE END OF THE 69TH WEEK OF DANIEL.
IF YOU KNOW THE PROPHECY IN DANIEL NINE.
>> I'VE MEMORIZED IT. IT'S POWERFUL.
IT'S THERE WERE 69 SYMBIOTIC CYCLES FROM CYRUS TO THE
ANOINTING OF CHRIST WHICH WAS 28 A.D. THAT MEANS BACKING UP
70 YEARS OR TEN SABBATICAL CYCLES FROM THE START OF THE
TIMES OF THE GENTILES WHEN THE BABYLONIANS DESTROYED THE THE
TEMPLE YOU HAD 79 WEEKS OR 550 THREE YEARS DO THE MATH 1776
IT'S AMAZING WAS 2300 YEARS. >> THIS IS TRULY THE BOOK OF
DANIEL. YOU'VE HEARD OF DANIEL, RIGHT?
>> I MEAN HE REALLY YOU SHOULD READ THAT BOOK THE THE FIRST
REFERENCE THAT CHRIST SAID WAS OUT OF HIS MOUTH WAS A
REFERENCE TO THAT INCREDIBLE BOOK THE TIME IS FULFILLED.
HE WAS TALKING ABOUT THERE BEING 69 WEEKS 483 YEARS
AND HERE'S SOMETHING THAT'S STRANGE.
483 YEARS IS 176,411 DAYS BUT 490 YEARS IF YOU USE THE 360
DAY CALENDAR IT'S THE SAME THING.
IT'S 176,400 DAYS BASICALLY THE SAME THING.
>> EVERYONE SHOULD BE CORRECTED AND THERE'S NO REASON FOR IT.
>> ALL RIGHT. SO LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER. PLEASE PLEASE COME FORWARD.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON. ELECTED MEMBERS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS GERALDINE ANDERSON.
I'M A DEDICATED VETERAN CITY AND COUNTY EMPLOYEE FOR OVER 36
YEARS OF SERVICE AND THE AUTHOR OF TWO EMAILS WRITTEN TO
CHAIRWOMAN OF THE BUDGET AND FINANCE COMMITTEE
SUPERVISOR CHAN IN A SHARED EMAIL TO MAYOR LURIE AND THE
REST OF THE BOARD. I RESPECTFULLY COME BEFORE YOU
TODAY ON BEHALF OF THE MOST SENIOR STAFF 42 EMPLOYEES TO BE
EXACT OF THE SAN FRANCISCO'S SUPERIOR COURT WHOSE
EMPLOYMENT, TENURE AND RETIREMENT BENEFITS ARE
MONITORED AND CONTROLLED BY THIS GREAT CITY.
I'M HOPEFUL ALL OF YOU HAVE RECEIVED THE PACKET I FILED ON
JULY 3RD WITH THIS OFFICE REQUESTING FOR A CONSIDERATION
OF A VOLUNTARY RETIREMENT INCENTIVE.
I MAKE THIS STATEMENT THIS VOLUNTEER FREE RETIREMENT
INCENTIVE WOULD ALLOW FOR A COST SAVINGS FOR THE COURT,
AVOID UNNECESSARY FURLOUGHS OR LAYOFFS AND MOST IMPORTANTLY
CONTINUING AND DELAYED PUBLIC ACCESS TO OUR JUSTICE SYSTEM.
I HUMBLY PRAY THIS CITY LEADERSHIP WILL CHAMPION THIS
REQUEST AND RECOGNIZE OUR EFFORTS IN PRESERVING THE CIVIC
INFRASTRUCTURE OUR COURTS PROVIDE.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER. >> OH, HI.
I'M MARY RICK PERRY AND I'M PROBABLY SORT OF THE SUPERIOR
COURT OF SAN FRANCISCO OVER 18 YEARS.
I STRONGLY SUPPORT THE IMPLEMENTATION SHOT OF THE
THREE PLUS THREE VOLUNTARY RETIREMENT INCENTIVE.
>> THIS PROPOSAL PRESENTS A FISCALLY RESPONSIBLE SOLUTION
THAT ALIGNS WITH OUR SHARED COMMITMENT TO PRESERVING PUBLIC
SERVICES WHILE ADDRESSING BUDGETARY CONSTRAINTS.
BY OFFERING THIS INCENTIVE, THE COURT CAN ACHIEVE MEANINGFUL
COST SAVINGS, PREVENT DISRUPTIVE PAULOSE OR LAYOFFS
AND MOST IMPORTANTLY ENSURE UNINTERRUPTED PUBLIC ACCESS TO
JUSTICE. IT IS A STRONG TEACHING
INVESTMENT IN BOTH THE WELL-BEING OF DEDICATED STAFF
AND THE COMMUNITIES WE SERVE. I URGE YOU TO CONSIDER THIS
PROPOSAL AS A PROACTIVE STEP TOWARD STABILIZING OUR
WORKFORCE AND MAINTAINING THE INTEGRITY OF OUR JUSTICE SYSTEM
. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. ARE THERE ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF
THE PUBLIC TO ADDRESS THE BOARD DURING GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT?
PLEASE STEP UP. THIS MAY BE OUR LAST SPEAKER.
WELCOME SIR. >> THANK YOU.
BOARD MEMBERS AND BOARD PRESIDENT THERE'S A REAL COLD
WIND COMING FROM WASHINGTON AND D.C. AND IT'S FLAMING.
OUR STATE PARTICULARLY LOS ANGELES AS YOU'VE SEEN THE NEWS
. AND I REALLY DON'T THINK THAT
THE PEOPLE IN SAN FRANCISCO ARE PREPARED FOR WHAT POTENTIALLY
IS COMING. THE LOS ANGELES EVENTS ARE
SIMPLY A PRACTICE IN FACT. WHILE YOU ALL THINK THAT
SANCTUARY CITY IS GOING TO SAVE YOU, IT'S PROBABLY GOING TO BE
A FIGHT, FIGHT, FIGHT. SO YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO MAKE
AS I SAID LAST WEEK SOME KIND OF COMPROMISES TO KEEP FIGHTING
. I READ IN THE NEWSPAPER THIS
MAY BE A SIGN OF THE TIMES THAT A BANK EMPLOYEE WAS ARRESTED
FOR FOR EXTORTING RATHER EMBEZZLING $500,000 WHICH IS
HALF $1 MILLION. >> BUT WHAT WAS INTERESTING
ABOUT THAT ARTICLE THAT THE BANK ITSELF WAS NOT NAMED.
IS THAT AN INFLUENCE OF THE THINGS THAT WERE GOING TO SEE
IN THE FUTURE? ANOTHER ONE THAT KIND OF NOTED
ME IN A NOTE MADE I NOTED WAS THE DIVISIVENESS THAT OUR
DISTRICTS ARE HAVING IN CARVING OUT SPECIAL ZONES FOR EACH
OTHER. FOR EXAMPLE THE NORTH BEACH
ZONE THIS IS PROBABLY A LEGACY FROM OUR LAST SUPERVISOR
PRESIDENT AARON PESKIN AND OF COURSE THE MISSION 24TH STREET
WHICH IS ANOTHER SHORT ZONE BUT A SPECIAL DISTRICT.
WE CAN'T HAVE THESE SPECIAL DISTRICTS.
WE'VE GOT TO GET UNITED UNITED WE STAND, DIVIDED WE FALL.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS .
ALL RIGHT. WELCOME, SIR.
ARE YOU OUR LAST SPEAKER? EXCUSE ME.
>> IS THE SUBJECT OF OCEAN AVENUE CLOSED?
NO, THIS IS NOT ABOUT THE OCEAN AVENUE CBD.
THIS IS GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT. I CAN COMMENT ON OCEAN AVENUE.
>> NO, SIR. OKAY.
THANK YOU. >> ALL RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT.
ALL RIGHT. PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED.
>> WE ARE GOING TO SKIP OVER THE CLOSED SESSION ITEM 45 FOR
NOW AND CALL IT UP AT THE END OF OUR AGENDA.
MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO OUR FOR ADOPTION OF THAT COMMITTEE
REFERENCE. >> AGENDA ITEMS 46 THROUGH 50
ITEMS 46 THROUGH 50 WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION BUT
WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED FOR
ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST READING TODAY.
ALTERNATIVELY, A MEMBER MAY REQUIRE A RESOLUTION ON FIRST
READING TO GO TO COMMITTEE. >> SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU
MR. PRESIDENT. I LIKE THE CIVIL 49 AND 54 950
ARE SEVERED AND MADAM CLERK CAN YOU OKAY.
>> SUPERVISOR DORSEY 47 AND 47. SO, MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS 46 AND 48 ON ITEMS 4648 AND 50.
>> MR. PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN
CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR
AND ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I.
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI
GENTLEMEN I'M SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I AND SUPERVISOR WALTON HI WALTON
I THERE ARE 11 EYES ALL RIGHT WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
47 ITEM 47 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO URGE THE UNIVERSITY OF
CALIFORNIA HEALTH AND BLUE SHIELD OF CALIFORNIA TO RESOLVE
DISPUTE REGARDING REIMBURSEMENT FOR MEDICAL SERVICES
AND TREATMENT BY RENEWING THEIR CONTRACT, THEREBY CONTINUING TO
PRESERVE MEMBERS ABILITY TO ACCESS CRUCIAL HEALTH CARE
SERVICES. >> SUPERVISOR DORSEY, THANK YOU
PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN COLLEAGUES EARLIER THIS AFTERNOON
LITERALLY MOMENTS AFTER CONFIRMING THAT THIS RESOLUTION
ENJOYED THE UNANIMOUS CO-SPONSORSHIP OF THIS BOARD,
MY OFFICE RECEIVED WORD FROM THE SAN FRANCISCO HEALTH
SERVICE SYSTEM WHOSE BOARD I SERVE ON THAT THE DISPUTE
BETWEEN UC HEALTH AND BLUE SHIELD OF CALIFORNIA THAT WE
WERE URGING TO BE RESOLVED HAS IN FACT BEEN RESOLVED.
SO THIS IS OBVIOUSLY GREAT NEWS FOR THE CITY WORKERS
AND RETIREES AND NO SMALL NUMBER OF OUR CONSTITUENTS WHO
WILL NOT BE LOSING ACCESS TO UCSF DOCTORS AND SERVICES.
I WOULD LIKE TO THINK THAT THIS HAPPENED PRECISELY BECAUSE OF
OUR UNANIMITY. BUT EVEN IF THAT'S NOT THE
CASE, YOUR SUPPORT CERTAINLY DIDN'T HURT THE BLUE SHIELD.
UC'S CONTRACT WILL BE RENEWED, THEREBY CONTINUING TO PRESERVE
MEMBERS ABILITY TO ACCESS CRUCIAL HEALTH CARE SERVICES.
I WANT TO THANK ALL COLLEAGUES ESPECIALLY SUPERVISORS MELGAR
WHO LIKE ME REPRESENTS A LARGE PART OF UC'S FOOTPRINT IN THE
CITY AND FROM HER TEAM MIKE FERRER AND OF COURSE MY OWN
LEGISLATIVE AIDE MIKE BRYANT ALL FOR HIS TIRELESS EFFORTS ON
HEALTH SERVICES FOR OUR WORKERS, FOR OUR RETIREES
AND FOR OUR RESIDENTS. ALL RIGHT.
SUPERVISOR DORSEY SO SHALL WE GO AHEAD AND APPROVE THIS
IN COMMEMORATION OF YOUR SUCCESS?
CONGRATULATIONS, COLLEAGUES. WE CAN TAKE ITEM 47 SAME HOUSE,
SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
49. >> ITEM 40 NINE THIS IS A
RESOLUTION TO URGE THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO TO
ESTABLISH A SMALL BUSINESS RELIEF FUND FOR MERCHANTS
AFFECTED BY THE IS LEE A IS IS LEE IS CREEK BRIDGE REPLACEMENT
PROJECT ALONG THE THIRD STREET CORRIDOR.
>> SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU SO MUCH MR. PRESIDENT.
COLLEAGUES, I JUST WANT TO DRAW ATTENTION TO THE FACT THAT THE
UPCOMING IS LAST CREEK BRIDGE PROJECT IS GOING TO SHUT DOWN A
BIG STRETCH OF THIRD STREET FOR YEARS AND THAT'S GOING TO HIT
BAYVIEW SMALL BUSINESSES HARD. >> THESE ARE FAMILY RUN SPOTS
IMMIGRANT OWNED, BLACK OWNED AND THEY WILL DEPEND ON FOOT
TRAFFIC IMMUNITY TO STAY ALIVE AS WELL AS ALL OF THE FOLKS WHO
WILL BE AFFECTED BY TRAFFIC TRYING TO GET HOME ON A DAILY.
IF THE CITY IS GOING TO MOVE FORWARD WITH THIS PROJECT WE
NEED TO STEP UP NOW WITH REAL RELIEF SO THESE BUSINESSES CAN
MAKE IT THROUGH JUST LIKE HOW WE PROVIDE A RELIEF FOR THE
TERRIBLE L PROJECT, THE PROJECT ON VENICE AND DURING THE
PANDEMIC IF WE CAN FUND AND BUILD CLIMATE RESILIENT
INFRASTRUCTURE LIKE THE LAST BRIDGE, WE CAN ALSO FUND
RESILIENCE FOR OUR LOCAL ECONOMIES AND WORKING CLASS
NEIGHBORHOODS. THANK YOU FOR JOINING ME
IN SUPPORTING THIS RESOLUTION AND I LOOK FORWARD TO
PARTNERING WITH OUR DEPARTMENTS AND OUR MAYOR TO MAKE THIS A
REALITY FOR OUR SMALL BUSINESSES.
>> THANK YOU. SUPER AS ONE.
WE'LL TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> SUPERVISOR WALTON, DID YOU WANT TO TALK ABOUT 50 OR NO?
YOU DID, MADAM CLERK I THINK WE WE I MEAN I CALLED FOR TWO FOR
US TO VOTE ON 46 AND 48. I THINK WE MAY HAVE A DONE 50
SO WE SHALL WE WILL SEND THE VOTE.
>> I THINK YOU WANT TO RESCIND THE VOTE ON ITEM 50, MR.
PRESIDENT. YES.
OKAY. >> THANK YOU.
MOTION TO RESCIND THE VOTE YOU NEED TO SECOND MOTION BY CHERYL
SECONDED BY CHAN. WE CAN TAKE THAT.
CAN WE DO THAT WITHOUT OBJECTION?
YES, WE'LL DO THAT WITHOUT OBJECTION.
>> THE THE VOTE IS RESCINDED. >> AND SUPERVISOR WALTON, THANK
YOU SO MUCH PRESIDENT MADAM AND JUST WANTED COLLEAGUES TO
KNOW WHY WE WERE DOING THIS. BASICALLY WE HAVE GROUPS WHO
ARE WORKING TOGETHER TO COME TO A RESOLUTION.
THEY NEED A LITTLE BIT MORE TIME.
WE HAD THEM CONTINUE TO SET PLANNING.
WE'RE NOW APPROACHING THE DEADLINE TO WHERE WE HAVE TO
EXTEND THIS FOR IT TO BE VALID OR WE WOULD HAVE TO GO THROUGH
IT AND INTRODUCTION AGAIN. SO I'M ASKING FOR YOUR SUPPORT
ON A 90 DAY EXTENSION TO ALLOW THAT WORK TO CONTINUE BEFORE
THE PROJECT APPEARS THAT PLANNING AND THEN AT THE FULL
BOARD THANK YOU SUPERVISOR WALTON AND NOW I THINK WE CAN
TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED AND MS. TIM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR
CLOSED SESSION PLEASE CALL ITEM 45 ITEM 45 THIS IS A CONFERENCE
WITH THE CITY ATTORNEY. >> THIS IS A CLOSED SESSION FOR
THE BOARD TO CONVENE FOR THE PURPOSE OF CONFERRING WITH OR
RECEIVING ADVICE FROM THE CITY ATTORNEY PERTAINING TO EXISTING
LITIGATION IN WHICH THE CITY IS A PETITIONER AND PACIFIC GAS
AND ELECTRIC COMPANY IS AN ADVERSE PARTY.
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. SO WE'LL NOW GO INTO CLOSED
SESSION. >> WE'LL TAKE A MOMENT TO
PREPARE THE CHAMBER
S.F. GOV TV SAN FRANCISCO GOVERNMENT TELEVISION
S.F. GOV TV SAN FRANCISCO GO GOVERNMENT TELEVISION
AND S.F. GOV TV SAN FRANCISCO GOVERNMENT TELEVISION
S.F. GOV TV SAN FRANCISCO GOVERNMENT TELEVISION
. OKAY WE ARE BACK IN OPEN
SESSION MAY I HAVE A MOTION OF THE BOARD FINDS THAT IT IS
IN THE BEST INTEREST OF THE PUBLIC OF THE PORT THAT THE
BOARD ELECT NOT TO DISCLOSE ITS CLOSED SESSION DELIBERATIONS
AND THAT NO ACTION WAS TAKEN MOVED BY DORSEY SECONDED BY
CHAN. >> MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON THAT MOTION? >> SUPERVISOR CHAN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MY GOOD MAHMUT I SUPERVISOR
RANDLEMAN HI MIDDLEMAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I
SUPERVISOR SARDAR SAUTER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
AND SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I THERE ARE 11 EYES.
>> ALL RIGHT WITHOUT OBJECTION WE WILL NOT DISCLOSE OUR CLOSED
SESSION DELIBERATIONS AND WE SEE NO OTHER NAMES ON THE
ROSTER. THIS CLOSED SESSION HAS BEEN
HELD AND IS NOW FILED. AND MADAM CLERK LET'S GO BACK
TO ITEM 40. >> YES.
AND I'LL JUST SAY FOR AS OF GOV TV THIS IS THE RESOLUTION TO
ESTABLISH THE PROPERTY BASED BUSINESS IMPROVEMENT DISTRICT
KNOWN AS THE OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT
AND TO ORDER THE LEVY AND COLLECTION OF ASSESSMENTS
AGAINST PROPERTY LOCATED IN THE DISTRICT FOR 15 YEARS IT'S
AND THEN MADAM CLERK TWO I READ THE RESULTS ARE YOU READ THE
RESULTS? I HAVE THE RESULTS PRESENT.
WHAT ARE THE RESULTS? >> THE RETURNED WEIGHTED
BALLOTS VOTING FOR THE OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT
DISTRICT WAS 70.41% AND THE RETURNED WEIGHTED BALLOTS
VOTING AGAINST THE OCEAN AVENUE COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT WAS
29.59% FURTHER INDICATING THERE WAS NO MAJORITY PROTEST.
>> ALL RIGHT. SO GIVEN THAT THERE WAS NO
MAJORITY PROTEST MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON
ITEM NUMBER 40? OKAY.
AND SO MR. PRESIDENT, ON ITEM 40 RESOLUTION AS AMENDED
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO
AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI.
I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I AND SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
THERE ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED MADAM CLERK DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS?
>> I HAVE NONE TO REPORT. MR. PRESIDENT.
DO WE HAVE ANY IN MEMORIAM? I HAVE TO REPORT.
WELL THEN I BELIEVE THAT BRINGS US TO THE END OF OUR AGENDA.
DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS BEFORE US TODAY?
>> THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS FOR TODAY.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. WE ARE ADJOURNED